<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><head><style id="xml-viewer-style">/* Copyright 2014 The Chromium Authors
 * Use of this source code is governed by a BSD-style license that can be
 * found in the LICENSE file.
 */

:root {
  color-scheme: light dark;
}

div.header {
    border-bottom: 2px solid black;
    padding-bottom: 5px;
    margin: 10px;
}

@media (prefers-color-scheme: dark) {
  div.header {
    border-bottom: 2px solid white;
  }
}

div.folder &gt; div.hidden {
    display:none;
}

div.folder &gt; span.hidden {
    display:none;
}

.pretty-print {
    margin-top: 1em;
    margin-left: 20px;
    font-family: monospace;
    font-size: 13px;
}

#webkit-xml-viewer-source-xml {
    display: none;
}

.opened {
    margin-left: 1em;
}

.comment {
    white-space: pre;
}

.folder-button {
    user-select: none;
    cursor: pointer;
    display: inline-block;
    margin-left: -10px;
    width: 10px;
    background-repeat: no-repeat;
    background-position: left top;
    vertical-align: bottom;
}

.fold {
    background: url("data:image/svg+xml,&lt;svg xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' fill='%23909090' width='10' height='10'&gt;&lt;path d='M0 0 L8 0 L4 7 Z'/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;");
    height: 10px;
}

.open {
    background: url("data:image/svg+xml,&lt;svg xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' fill='%23909090' width='10' height='10'&gt;&lt;path d='M0 0 L0 8 L7 4 Z'/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;");
    height: 10px;
}
</style></head><body><div id="webkit-xml-viewer-source-xml"><us-patent-application xmlns="" lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.3 2012-12-04" file="US20130078989A1-20130328.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20130313" date-publ="20130328">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20130078989</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20130328</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>13246285</doc-number>
<date>20110927</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>13</us-application-series-code>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20090101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>H</section>
<class>04</class>
<subclass>W</subclass>
<main-group>48</main-group>
<subgroup>08</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20130328</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classification-national>
<country>US</country>
<main-classification>4554221</main-classification>
</classification-national>
<invention-title id="d0e43">Neighbor List Distribution for Smart Mobility</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kubota</last-name>
<first-name>Keiichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Weybridge</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>GB</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
<us-applicant sequence="01" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Martin</last-name>
<first-name>Brian Alexander</first-name>
<address>
<city>Farnham</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>GB</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Kubota</last-name>
<first-name>Keiichi</first-name>
<address>
<city>Weybridge</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>Martin</last-name>
<first-name>Brian Alexander</first-name>
<address>
<city>Farnham</city>
<country>GB</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<orgname>Renesas Mobile Corporation</orgname>
<role>03</role>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">A user equipment UE receives from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells/frequencies, and at least one individual neighbor cell/frequency supports a plurality of frequency bands. The neighbor cells/frequencies are filtered to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or frequency bands which are also supported by the UE. Examples are given of various system information blocks for sending the frequency band indications to the UE. In one embodiment they are arranged in an information element IE having an entry for each of the neighbor cells/frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry. In another the IE has an index and an associated frequency band(s) where a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells/frequencies referred to by the index belong to the associated frequency band(s).</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="198.97mm" wi="178.22mm" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="223.10mm" wi="179.24mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="218.61mm" wi="158.41mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="214.63mm" wi="177.55mm" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="235.46mm" wi="192.19mm" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="252.81mm" wi="191.01mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20130078989A1-20130328-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The exemplary and non-limiting embodiments of this invention relate generally to wireless communication systems, methods, devices and computer programs and, more specifically, relate to neighbor cells which support multiple frequency bands.</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">The following abbreviations that may be found in the specification and/or the drawing figures are defined as follows:</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0000">
<tables id="TABLE-US-00001" num="00001">
<table frame="none" colsep="0" rowsep="0">
<tgroup align="left" colsep="0" rowsep="0" cols="3">
<colspec colname="offset" colwidth="14pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="1" colwidth="42pt" align="left"/>
<colspec colname="2" colwidth="161pt" align="left"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody valign="top">
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>3GPP</entry>
<entry>third generation partnership project</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>EARFCN</entry>
<entry>EUTRA absolute radio frequency channel number</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>EUTRA</entry>
<entry>evolved universal terrestrial radio access</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>IE</entry>
<entry>information element</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>LTE</entry>
<entry>long term evolution (EUTRA network)</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>LTE-A</entry>
<entry>LTE-advanced</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>RAN</entry>
<entry>radio access network</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>RF</entry>
<entry>radiofrequency</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>SI</entry>
<entry>system information</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>SIB</entry>
<entry>system information block</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>UARFCN</entry>
<entry>UTRA absolute radio frequency channel number</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>UMTS</entry>
<entry>universal mobile telecommunication system</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry>UE</entry>
<entry>user equipment</entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry/>
<entry namest="offset" nameend="2" align="center" rowsep="1"/>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</tables>
</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0003">Cellular radio communications now include individual cells operating on multiple radio frequency channels in order to better support a variety of different UEs, some of which may be capable of operating on only one of these frequency bands which is different than a band for which another UE in the cell is capable. Additionally, some bands in use by one cell may have some frequency portion overlapping with bands in an adjacent neighbor cell, particularly where such neighbor cells operate under different radio access technologies such as UMTS and LTE. For example, in the HSPA version of UMTS bands II and XXV have respective frequency bands 1930-1990 MHz and 1930-1995 MHz and thus are overlapping in frequency. There is a similar overlap among bands V (869-894 MHz), VI (875-885 MHz) and new band XXVI (814-849 and 859-894 MHz); bands IV (2110-2115 MHz) and X (2110-2170 MHz); and bands III (1805-1880 MHz) and IX (1844.9-1879.9 MHz).</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0004">Relevant to the above scenarios are certain proposals for LTE Release 10 set forth in document R2-114158 by Qualcomm entitled MULTIPLE HARMONISED BANDS PER CELL and in document R2-114299 by Ericsson and ST-Ericsson entitled MULTIPLE FREQUENCY BAND INDICATORS IN A CELL (both from 3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 meeting #75; Athens, Greece; 22-26 Aug. 2011). Specifically, these documents propose that some cells which belong to a frequency in an overlapping band will broadcast the multiple bands they support according to variously named extension fields for the SIB<b>1</b>. In the examples given there are in the context of a new band <b>26</b> which was recently introduced into Release 10 discussions. This broadcast that multiple bands are supported is to allow new UEs which support the new band <b>26</b> to relax their RF requirements as compared to the older defined bands so that when roaming onto an operators band they may then apply the new relaxed requirements, and thereby avoid the UE having to perform interoperability testing (IOT). These proposals are to additionally allow older UEs supporting the older bands to camp on the same cell as well as to allow legacy UEs to camp on the newer band. These proposals seek to adapt the requirement at section 5.4 of 3GPP TS 25.101 v10.2.0 (2011-06) that a cell is allowed to indicate in SI only one frequency band it supports.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0005">A problem arises in the above solutions when considering UE mobility between cells. A UE performs mobility based on a neighbor list given to it by SI. The conventional practice is that for UMTS the individual cells on each frequency are listed, and for LTE only the frequency is listed. But if the above proposals of introducing multiple bands support in a cell were adopted, the UE would not know whether the neighbor cell (UMTS) or neighbor frequency (LTE) belongs to a frequency band which the UE supports until after that UE reads SI from the target cell (specifically, SIB<b>5</b> if the target cell is UMTS and SIB<b>1</b> if the target cell is LTE). So in some cases the UE will give up on re-selecting to the neighbor cell because of a non-supported frequency band only after the UE performed some mobility related processes (such as neighbor cell measurement, cell quality evaluation, cell reselection, target cell SI reading), which depletes the battery or other portable power source of the UE. Since the UARFCN or EARFCN indicated in the neighbor cell/frequency list may belong to multiple bands, the UE cannot determine which band to which it refers.</p>
<p id="p-0008" num="0006">Further, the serving cell's broadcast of its own UARFCN/EARFCN referring to a specific frequency can be different for a different band; different UARFCN/EARFCN can refer to the same frequency but in a different band/channel. In this case the neighbor cell/frequency list which the UE uses for mobility purposes would need to be updated to broadcast the same frequency multiple times so that all UEs can reselect. But this then causes a problem in that there is a limited number of cells which can be broadcast in the UTRAN neighbor cell list. Even in some of today's networks, the size limitation imposed but the signalling restrictions of the UTRAN neighbor cell list can restrict the neighbor cell configuration therefore increasing the size further is not practical. This also causes a problem due to there being a maximum number of frequencies in UTRAN and/or EUTRAN which the UE which is required to measure. In UMTS the UE is required to be able to measure two frequencies in addition to the carrier (serving cell) frequency, and in LTE the UE is required to measure three frequencies in addition to the carrier frequency. If for example the serving cell supports three bands, the neighbor cell/frequency list size may increase by a factor of three. In principle the UE could measure three bands if the frequencies are all identical, but this is not required by current radio specifications because currently there is no possibility for a cell to belong to more than one band.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0007">For that reason this issue was not a concern in the past. While there were some overlapping frequency bands (for example, Band V and Band VI overlap) there was no practical situation that the Band V cell could be signalled as a neighbor cell of a Band VI serving cell and additionally there was no possibility for either the serving or neighbor cell to support multiple bands. The detailed teachings below resolve the above problem which is wasteful of the UE's limited power source.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0010" num="0008">The foregoing and other problems are overcome, and other advantages are realized, by the use of the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0009">In a first exemplary embodiment of the invention there is an apparatus comprising at least one processor; and at least one memory including computer program code. In this embodiment the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to: receive from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and filter the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0010">In a second exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a method comprising: receiving from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0011">In a third exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a computer readable memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor. In this embodiment the computer program comprises code for receiving in system information broadcast by a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and code for filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0012">In a fourth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is an apparatus comprising at least one processor; and at least one memory including computer program code. In this embodiment the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to: obtain frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and send to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0013">In a fifth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a method comprising: obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0014">In a sixth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a computer readable memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor. In this embodiment the computer program comprises code for obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and code for sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0017" num="0015"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view of a conceptual radio environment in which the various exemplary embodiments detailed herein may be practiced to advantage.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0016"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exemplary signaling diagram showing signaling and internal processes according to exemplary embodiments detailed herein.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0017"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> is a logic flow diagram illustrating from the perspective of the UE the operation of a method, and a result of execution of computer program instructions embodied on a computer readable memory, for practicing exemplary embodiments of these teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0018"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> is a logic flow diagram illustrating from the perspective of the serving cell/serving access node the operation of a method, and a result of execution of computer program instructions embodied on a computer readable memory, for practicing exemplary embodiments of these teachings.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0019"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> is a simplified block diagram of some of the devices shown at <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> which are exemplary electronic devices suitable for use in practicing the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0022" num="0020">While the two documents noted in the background section above refer to the cell broadcasting in its own SI the additional bands which it supports, those proposals do not go far enough. To avoid the UE undertaking certain mobility procedures as noted above which will in the end prove fruitless due to the UE's incompatibility with a neighbor cell, in an embodiment of these teachings the serving cell will broadcast in its SI an indication of the multiple frequency bands that its individual neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies support. For example, a UTRAN serving cell will broadcast in its own SI indications of the frequency bands which its neighbor UTRAN cells support and which its neighbor LTE frequencies support. For the case of a LTE serving cell it will broadcast in its own SI indications of the frequency bands which its neighbor frequencies (UTRAN and LTE) support. In this manner the UE can see the entire list of bands which each neighbor cell or frequency supports, and construct its own locally stored neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list (which it uses for its mobility choices) by filtering according to the UE's own capabilities on those channels/bands. Since the UE will have the relevant information before reading SI of the neighbor cell it can avoid performing mobility-related processes directed toward cell reselection to a neighbor cell to which it is incompatible. In case a network does not update the neighbor cell or frequency list the UE can still use the frequency band information in its previously-defined filtered list to avoid performing measurements in preparation for handover in a particular radio access technology. In these teachings a new cell which belongs to more than one frequency band can broadcast in the neighbor cell or frequency list that another cell or frequency also belongs to more than one frequency band, such as by indicating the frequency bands in the neighbors' UARFCN and/or EARFCN (depending on whether the neighbor cell is a UMTS or a LTE cell).</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0021">Before detailing further specific implementations, reference is made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 1</figref> for illustrating an exemplary radio environment in which these teachings can be practiced to advantage. There is a UE <b>20</b> operating in the vicinity of a serving cell <b>22</b> and there are multiple neighbor cells operating on multiple neighbor frequencies, of which neighbor cell <b>26</b> is exemplary. The specifics vary depending on whether the serving cell <b>22</b> and the neighbor cell <b>26</b> are operating in the UMTS or the LTE systems, but in general the serving cell <b>22</b> will broadcast in its system information indications about all of the frequency bands which the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies support. The UE <b>20</b> will of course get the SI broadcast from the serving cell <b>22</b> prior to performing any mobility-related procedures toward a given neighbor cell or neighbor frequency. From the list of frequency bands for the neighbor cells/frequencies the UE <b>20</b> will determine which if any of those bands it supports. The UE <b>20</b> will then construct the neighbor cell list using all the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies it learned from the SI of its serving cell <b>22</b>, excluding those the UE <b>20</b> does not support. When the UE needs to perform some neighbor cell measurement, cell reselection, or other mobility-related process, it will use only those channels on the neighbor cell list that it constructed by filtering using the UE's own capabilities, and so all neighbor cells and frequencies on the UE's locally stored list will be viable to use for cell reselection (assuming sufficient signal strength and other dynamic parameters of the radio environment).</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0022"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 2</figref> is an exemplary signaling diagram illustrating signaling and internal processes in the serving cell <b>22</b> and the UE <b>20</b> according to the above overview. At <b>202</b> the serving cell <b>22</b> broadcasts its SI, which according to these teachings includes the frequency band information for the UARFCN and/or the EARFCN of each of its neighbor cells/frequencies. At <b>204</b> the UE <b>20</b>, having received the serving cell's broadcast SI <b>202</b>, then filters all of those neighbor cells/frequencies according to the UE's own frequency band capabilities. Each band the UE supports gets filtered in and each band it does not gets filtered out. In one embodiment the UE <b>20</b> constructs its neighbor cell list with this filtering and stores it in its local memory for use in the cell. That neighbor cell list will include every neighbor cell frequency band that the UE <b>20</b> learned from the serving cell's SI <b>202</b>, as filtered at <b>204</b> to exclude all bands which the UE <b>20</b> does not support. If for example a particular neighbor cell <b>26</b> is assigned to only one frequency band according to the serving cell's SI <b>202</b> and if the UE does not support the frequency band, then the UE <b>20</b> can exclude the cell from its neighbor cell list. If for example the neighbor cell <b>26</b> supports three frequency bands which the UE <b>20</b> learns at <b>202</b> from the serving cell's SI and the UE <b>20</b> supports two of them, then the UE <b>20</b> will include the cell into the neighbor cell list, and it keeps those two frequency bands in its memory. The UE <b>20</b> uses the neighbor cell list to select which cells/frequencies to measure and re-select on. The reader will recognize that typically there will be multiple neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies whose frequency band or bands (as the case may be) are indicated by the SI of the serving cell <b>22</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0023">In another embodiment the UE <b>20</b> stores the list it receives from the network, and filters at block <b>204</b> on a case by case basis anytime the UE <b>20</b> is about to start a mobility related procedure, and continues that procedure only if the band relevant to the procedure passes the UE-capability filtering. In this embodiment the UE does not store the filtered list but runs a stored algorithm that filters the network-supplied list each time it's needed and the same result is obtained. However the filtering of block <b>204</b> is implemented, at <b>206</b> the UE uses only the neighbor cells/frequencies which are indicated to support a frequency band which is also supported by the UE itself for any mobility related procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0024">From the network perspective, if the neighbor cell <b>26</b> is a UMTS cell the serving cell <b>22</b> signals the frequency band information for the UARFCN of that UMTS neighbor cell in the system information broadcasted on the serving cell's broadcast control channel. If the neighbor cell <b>26</b> is an LTE cell the serving cell <b>22</b> signals the frequency band information for the EARFCN of the neighbor frequencies in the serving cell's system information. In case the frequency is associated with different bands, the serving cell <b>22</b> will signal all of the potential bands that can be found on that frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0025">From the UE's perspective, the UE <b>20</b> will collect all of the neighbor cells' associated frequency bands signaled in the serving cell's SI. For those neighbor cells which are UMTS cells the UE <b>20</b> checks that neighbor cell's frequency band information before performing any mobility procedures to that neighbor cell. For a neighbor cell for which all of its assigned frequency bands are not supported by the UE <b>20</b>, the UE <b>20</b> simply discards the UTRAN neighbor cell from its locally stored list. That is, the UE <b>20</b> will not attempt any mobility procedure to move to that neighbor UMTS cell whose frequency band or frequency bands the UE <b>20</b> does not support. For a neighbor UMTS cell whose frequency band the UE does support, the UE <b>20</b> may perform the necessary mobility procedures for that neighbor UMTS cell (assuming it is a good cell reselection candidate in other respects such as signal strength).</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0026">Again from the UE's perspective, for those neighbor frequencies which are associated with LTE cells the UE <b>20</b> simply does not attempt to measure or perform any mobility procedures on that frequency if the UE <b>20</b> does not support the frequency bands indicated in the serving cell's SI. This is similar to the UMTS cell procedure except that the LTE cell frequency band information is always given per frequency instead of per cell. There may be cases where there is a mixture of different frequency band cells on one frequency. To address that case the serving cell <b>22</b> can signal in its SI the cell PCI range, a list of each frequency band on a cell or frequency, in order to optimize the UE mobility/reselection attempts. This case is expected to be atypical and likely not even needed due to the increased signalling overhead in SI it represents.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0027">There are multiple ways to implement this increased signaling in the serving cell's SI. The following examples do so by adding an information element to the serving cell's system information which includes a list of frequency band information for all the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies which support more than one frequency band. For example, if the serving cell <b>22</b> is UMTS it can add that new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band UMTS neighbor cell(s) in the serving cell's system information block type <b>11</b> (SIB<b>11</b>) or system information block type <b>11</b>bis (SIB<b>11</b>bis) or possibly its system information block type <b>12</b> (SIB<b>12</b>), and can also add that new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band LTE neighbor frequencies in its system information block type <b>19</b> (SIB<b>19</b>). If the serving cell <b>22</b> is LTE it can add the new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band LTE neighbor frequencies in the serving cell's system information block type <b>3</b> (SIB<b>3</b>). The number of entries in this new IE is the same as the number of neighbor cells for UMTS and the number of neighbor frequencies for LTE. Each entry indicates the frequency band(s) associated with the corresponding neighbor cell or neighbor frequency in the neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list. When the UE <b>20</b> filters the network supplied neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list, the UE <b>20</b> excludes the cells/frequencies not belonging to the UE supported frequency bands. Then the UE <b>20</b> performs cell reselection only on the filtered neighbor cell list or the filtered neighbor frequency list.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0028">In another embodiment the IE is added by the UMTS serving cell <b>22</b> to its SIB<b>11</b> or SIB<b>11</b>bis (and possibly also its SIB<b>12</b>) for the UMTS neighbor cells and in its SIB<b>19</b> for its LTE neighbor frequencies. Or if the serving cell <b>22</b> is an LTE cell it can add the new IE to its SIB<b>3</b> for all its neighbor frequencies. In these embodiments the IE can indicate an index and one or more frequency bands for each neighbor cell/frequency. The index, X for example, would indicate that the neighbor cells/frequencies from the 1<sup>st </sup>neighbor cell/frequency to the X<sup>th </sup>neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list belong to the frequency band(s) signalled in the same new IE. If more than one new IE is included in the SIB, then the subsequent IE's index, Y for example, would indicate that the neighbor cells/frequencies from (the previous IE's index +1)<sup>th </sup>neighbor cell/frequency to the Y<sup>th </sup>neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list belong to the frequency band(s) signalled in the same IE. This can be repeated for additional indices. The UE <b>20</b> would then filter and exclude as in the above paragraph and perform cell reselection using its filtered neighbor cell/frequency list.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0029">In another embodiment instead of a new IE in an existing SIB the information on the neighbor cell frequency bands is informed to the UE's via a new SIB, for example SIB<b>21</b> in the case of UMTS cells and SIB<b>14</b> in the case of LTE frequencies. Including the IE similar to that noted above in one or both of these new SIBs is a simple way to present the frequency band information to the UEs. In one implementation there is one entry in this new IE for each of the neighbor cells/frequencies, and each entry indicates the frequency band(s) associated with the corresponding neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list. In another implementation the IE indicates the index and the frequency band(s) for each neighbor cell/frequency as detailed above.</p>
<p id="p-0032" num="0030">One technical effect of these teachings is that the UE <b>20</b> can identify from its serving cell SI which neighbor cells/frequencies, including all cells/frequencies on a frequency band, can be considered as a candidate suitable cell/frequency for cell reselection before performing any mobility procedures. This saves on UE battery consumption as noted in the background section above. Relatedly, implementing these teachings are seen to result in more effective cell reselection by the UE since there will be fewer failed/aborted cell reselections.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0031">On the network side one technical effect is that the network operator can deploy multiple harmonized band cells without affecting UE battery life. The size of the neighbor cell/frequency list is unaffected, and so there is no need to utilize additional entries to refer to the same cell since the additional frequency band information can extend the applicability of a single UARFCN/EARFCN to refer to multiple bands. For this reason implementation of these teachings is not seen to affect the stipulated performance requirements.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref> are logic flow diagrams which may each be considered to illustrate the operation of a method, and a result of execution of a computer program stored in a computer readable memory, and a specific manner in which components of an electronic device are configured to cause that electronic device to operate. The various blocks shown in each of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref> may also be considered as a plurality of coupled logic circuit elements constructed to carry out the associated function(s), or specific result of strings of computer program code stored in a memory.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0033">Such blocks and the functions they represent are non-limiting examples, and may be practiced in various components such as integrated circuit chips and modules, and that the exemplary embodiments of this invention may be realized in an apparatus that is embodied as an integrated circuit. The integrated circuit, or circuits, may comprise circuitry (as well as possibly firmware) for embodying at least one or more of a data processor or data processors, a digital signal processor or processors, baseband circuitry and radio frequency circuitry that are configurable so as to operate in accordance with the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> details particular exemplary embodiments of the invention from the perspective of the UE. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> may be implemented by the entire UE or by one or more components thereof, more generally termed an apparatus. At block <b>302</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> the UE receives from its serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported. At block <b>304</b> the UE <b>20</b> filters the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by the UE itself. As in the above examples the UE may filter to generate a new list which it stores in its local memory and checks each time it needs to run a mobility procedure on a new band, or it may store the network-provided neighbor cell/frequency list and filter out those which only support a band or bands for which the UE is not capable on an as needed basis when checking each new neighbor cell/frequency for a mobility related procedure.</p>
<p id="p-0037" num="0035">Further portions of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> are optional and may or may not be combined with one another in various embodiments. Block <b>306</b> details that the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell and the at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell. Block <b>308</b> specifies that the system information comprises at least one of system information block types <b>11</b>, <b>11</b>bis, <b>12</b>, <b>19</b> and <b>3</b> as detailed in the examples above.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0036">Block <b>310</b> specifies one embodiment of the IE above, that the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry. Block <b>312</b> specifies another embodiment of the IE above, that the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index (X) indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells/frequencies referred to by the index (1<sup>st </sup>through the Xth) belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index. There can of course be more than one index in the IE of this embodiment with different indices referring to a different plurality of neighbor cells/frequencies and associated with a different band or bands.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0037">From the above description and examples, the UE functioning according to the <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 3</figref> embodiment is configured to utilize that filtered neighbor cell/neighbor frequency list for its own cell reselection processes.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0038"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> details particular exemplary embodiments of the invention from the perspective of the serving cell <b>22</b> which sends its SI with all of the neighbor cells' or neighbor frequencys' associated frequency bands. <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> may be implemented by the entire serving cell (more generally a wireless network access node) or by one or more components thereof, which is also more generally termed an apparatus. At block <b>402</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> the serving cell obtains frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands. The serving cell may determine this band information itself such as by collecting that information from the neighbor cells directly via an X2 or similar interface, or the neighbor cells and associated frequency bands may be obtained from a higher network node such as a radio network controller or mobility management entity. At block <b>402</b> the ‘individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency’ is used to better specify that from among the whole neighbor cell/frequency list the serving cell compiles, there is at least one of them which supports multiple frequency bands since not all of the neighbor cells/frequencies may be multi-band capable. However the serving cell obtains this frequency band data, it then at block <b>404</b> sends to UEs indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0039">Further portions of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 4</figref> are optional and may or may not be combined with one another in various embodiments. Block <b>406</b> states as with the above exemplary examples that the indications are sent to the UEs in system information broadcast by the serving cell, and the at least one individual neighbor cell/neighbor frequency is a neighbor cell/frequency to the serving cell. Block <b>408</b> recites the SIBs from the above examples: the indications are added to at least one of system information block types <b>11</b>, <b>11</b>bis, <b>12</b>, <b>19</b> and <b>3</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0040">Blocks <b>410</b> and <b>412</b> give the different embodiments of the new IE that are detailed above. At block <b>410</b> the serving cell sends the indications of block <b>404</b> by first arranging the indications in an IE having an entry for each of the neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry, and then sends the IE in SI. The other embodiment from the above examples is at block <b>412</b>, the sending of block <b>404</b> is implemented by the serving cell first arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies that are referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and then the serving cell sends this IE in its SI.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0041">Reference is now made to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> for illustrating a simplified block diagram of various electronic devices and apparatus that are suitable for use in practicing the exemplary embodiments of this invention. In <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. 5</figref> there is a serving cell/serving network access node <b>22</b> and a neighbor cell/neighbor network access node <b>26</b>, which are adapted for communication over respective wireless links <b>21</b>, <b>23</b> with an apparatus <b>20</b> such as mobile terminals or termed more generally as a user equipment UE. In certain networks such as LTE there is also an interface <b>27</b> between the serving <b>22</b> and neighbor <b>26</b> cell. The illustrated neighbor cell <b>26</b> stands in the place of the ‘at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency’ noted above for <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. 3-4</figref>, but there are typically other neighbor cells/frequencies to the serving cell <b>22</b> some or all of which may also support multiple frequency bands. The serving cell <b>22</b> may be further communicatively coupled via link <b>25</b> to a higher network node <b>24</b> such as a mobility management entity/serving gateway MME/S-GW <b>24</b> in the case of the LTE system or a radio network controller in the case of the UMTS system.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0042">The UE <b>20</b> includes processing means such as at least one data processor (DP) <b>20</b>A, storing means such as at least one computer-readable memory (MEM) <b>20</b>B storing at least one computer program (PROG) <b>20</b>C, communicating means such as a transmitter TX <b>20</b>D and a receiver RX <b>20</b>E for bidirectional wireless communications with the serving cell <b>22</b> and with the neighbor cell <b>26</b> via one or more antennas <b>20</b>F. Within the memory <b>20</b>B of the UE <b>20</b> but shown separately as reference number <b>20</b>G is also a computer program for filtering, according to the UE capabilities, the list of neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies which the UE <b>20</b> receives from the serving cell's system information as is detailed above in various embodiments.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0043">The serving cell <b>22</b> also includes processing means such as at least one data processor (DP) <b>22</b>A, storing means such as at least one computer-readable memory (MEM) <b>22</b>B storing at least one computer program (PROG) <b>22</b>C, and communicating means such as a transmitter TX <b>22</b>D and a receiver RX <b>22</b>E for bidirectional wireless communications with its associated user devices <b>20</b> via one or more antennas <b>22</b>F and a modem. The serving cell <b>22</b> also has stored in its memory at <b>22</b>G software to assemble in its system information broadcasts all of the neighbor cells/frequencies and all of their associated frequency bands as is detailed by example above. The serving cell <b>26</b> is similarly functional with blocks <b>26</b>A, <b>26</b>B, <b>26</b>C, <b>26</b>D, <b>26</b>E and <b>26</b>F, but its block <b>26</b>G simply has its own multi-channel capability which the serving cell <b>22</b> learns via the interface <b>27</b> (if the LTE system) or via the higher network node <b>24</b>/radio network controller (if a UMTS system). But note that the neighbor cell <b>26</b> has the same functionality according to these teachings as the serving cell <b>22</b> which it uses when sending its own SI to its UEs. By example, the serving cell <b>22</b> may be a node B (UMTS) or an e-NodeB (LTE), the neighbor cell <b>26</b> may be a node B (UMTS) or an e-NodeB (LTE), and in the case of the LTE system the interface <b>27</b> may be an X2 interface between them.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0044">For completeness the higher network node <b>24</b> is also shown to include a DP <b>24</b>A, and a MEM <b>24</b>B storing a PROG <b>24</b>C, and additionally a modem <b>24</b>H for communicating with at least the serving cell <b>22</b> (to show embodiments in which the neighbor cell is not under the same higher network node). While not particularly illustrated for the UE <b>20</b> or cells <b>22</b>, <b>26</b>, those devices are also assumed to include as part of their wireless communicating means a modem which may in one exemplary but non limiting embodiment be inbuilt on an RF front end chip so as to carry the respective TX <b>20</b>D/<b>22</b>D/<b>26</b>D and RX <b>20</b>E/<b>22</b>E/<b>26</b>E.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0045">At least one of the PROGs <b>20</b>C, <b>22</b>C, <b>26</b>C in the UE <b>20</b> and in the serving and neighbor cells <b>22</b>, <b>26</b> is assumed to include program instructions that, when executed by the associated DP <b>20</b>A, <b>22</b>A, <b>26</b>A, enable the device to operate in accordance with the exemplary embodiments of this invention as detailed more fully above. In this regard the exemplary embodiments of this invention may be implemented at least in part by computer software stored on the MEM <b>20</b>B, <b>22</b>B, <b>26</b>B which is executable by the DP <b>20</b>A, <b>22</b>A, <b>26</b>A of the respective devices <b>20</b>, <b>22</b>, <b>26</b>; or by hardware; or by a combination of tangibly stored software and hardware (and tangibly stored firmware). Electronic devices implementing these aspects of the invention need not be the entire UE <b>20</b>, or serving cell <b>22</b>, or neighbor cell <b>26</b>, but exemplary embodiments may be implemented by one or more components of same such as the above described tangibly stored software, hardware, firmware and DP, or a system on a chip SOC or an application specific integrated circuit ASIC or a digital signal processor DSP or a modem or a subscriber identity module commonly referred to as a SIM card.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0046">Various embodiments of the UE <b>20</b> can include, but are not limited to: cellular telephones; data cards, USB dongles, personal portable digital devices having wireless communication capabilities including but not limited to laptop/palmtop/tablet computers, digital cameras and music devices, and Internet appliances.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0047">Various embodiments of the computer readable MEM <b>20</b>B, <b>22</b>B, <b>26</b>B include any data storage technology type which is suitable to the local technical environment, including but not limited to semiconductor based memory devices, magnetic memory devices and systems, optical memory devices and systems, fixed memory, removable memory, disc memory, flash memory, DRAM, SRAM, EEPROM and the like. Various embodiments of the DP <b>20</b>A, <b>22</b>A, <b>26</b>A include but are not limited to general purpose computers, special purpose computers, microprocessors, digital signal processors (DSPs) and multi-core processors.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0048">Various modifications and adaptations to the foregoing exemplary embodiments of this invention may become apparent to those skilled in the relevant arts in view of the foregoing description. While the exemplary embodiments have been described above in the context of the UMTS and LTE/LTE-A systems, it should be appreciated that the exemplary embodiments of this invention are not limited for use with only this one particular type of wireless communication system, and that they may be used to advantage in other wireless communication systems such as for example WCDMA and others which may interface with a neighbor cell that supports multiple frequency bands.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0049">Some of the various features of the above non-limiting embodiments may be used to advantage without the corresponding use of other described features. The foregoing description should therefore be considered as merely illustrative of the principles, teachings and exemplary embodiments of this invention, and not in limitation thereof.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. An apparatus comprising at least one processor; and
<claim-text>at least one memory including computer program code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>filter the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or frequency bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell and the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, in which the system information comprises at least one of system information block types <b>11</b>, <b>11</b>bis, <b>12</b>, <b>19</b> and <b>3</b>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, in which the apparatus comprises the user equipment which is configured to utilize only the filtered neighbor cells or frequencies for cell reselection.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. A method, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. A memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor, in which the computer program comprises:
<claim-text>code for receiving in system information broadcast by a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>code for filtering the frequency bands to retain only those indicated frequency bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The memory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. The memory according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00011">claim 11</claim-ref>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. An apparatus comprising
<claim-text>at least one processor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one memory including computer program code;</claim-text>
<claim-text>in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>send to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, in which the indications are sent to the user equipments in system information broadcast by the apparatus which comprises a serving cell, and the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00015">claim 15</claim-ref>, in which the system information comprises at least one of system information block types <b>11</b>, <b>11</b>bis, <b>12</b>, <b>19</b> and <b>3</b>.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured with the at least one processor to cause the apparatus to send to the user equipments the indications by:
<claim-text>arranging the indications in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the information element in system information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The apparatus according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00014">claim 14</claim-ref>, in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured with the at least one processor to cause the apparatus to send to the user equipments the indications by:
<claim-text>arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the information element in system information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. A method comprising:
<claim-text>obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00020" num="00020">
<claim-text><b>20</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, in which the indications are sent to the user equipments in broadcast system information, and the at least one individual neighbor cell is an neighbor cell or frequency to a serving cell executing the method.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00021" num="00021">
<claim-text><b>21</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref>, in which sending to the user equipments the indications comprises:
<claim-text>arranging the indications in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the information element in system information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00022" num="00022">
<claim-text><b>22</b>. The method according to <claim-ref idref="CLM-00019">claim 19</claim-ref> or <claim-ref idref="CLM-00020">20</claim-ref>, in which sending to the user equipments the indications comprises:
<claim-text>arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending the information element in system information.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00023" num="00023">
<claim-text><b>23</b>. A memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor, in which the computer program comprises:
<claim-text>code for obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>code for sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application></div><div class="header"><span>This XML file does not appear to have any style information associated with it. The document tree is shown below.</span><br /></div><div class="pretty-print"><div class="folder" id="folder0"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-patent-application<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">lang</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EN</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">dtd-version</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">v4.3 2012-12-04</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328.XML</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">status</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">PRODUCTION</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-patent-application</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">country</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">date-produced</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">20130313</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">date-publ</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">20130328</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder1"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-bibliographic-data-application<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">lang</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EN</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">country</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder2"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;publication-reference&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder3"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;document-id&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;doc-number&gt;</span><span>20130078989</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/doc-number&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;kind&gt;</span><span>A1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/kind&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20130328</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/document-id&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/publication-reference&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder4"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;application-reference<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">appl-type</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">utility</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder5"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;document-id&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;doc-number&gt;</span><span>13246285</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/doc-number&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20110927</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/document-id&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/application-reference&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-application-series-code&gt;</span><span>13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-application-series-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder6"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classifications-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder7"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder8"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20090101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-level&gt;</span><span>A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-level&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>04</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>W</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>48</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>08</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>F</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder9"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20130328</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder10"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classifications-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder11"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-national&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-classification&gt;</span><span>4554221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-classification&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-national&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;invention-title<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">d0e43</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Neighbor List Distribution for Smart Mobility</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/invention-title&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder12"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-parties&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder13"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-applicants&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder14"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-applicant<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">app-type</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">applicant</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder15"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>Kubota</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Keiichi</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder16"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Weybridge</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder17"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;residence&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/residence&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-applicant&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder18"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-applicant<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">01</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">app-type</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">applicant</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder19"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>Martin</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Brian Alexander</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder20"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Farnham</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder21"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;residence&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/residence&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-applicant&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-applicants&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder22"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventors&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder23"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventor<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder24"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>Kubota</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Keiichi</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder25"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Weybridge</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventor&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder26"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventor<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">01</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder27"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>Martin</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Brian Alexander</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder28"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Farnham</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>GB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventor&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventors&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-parties&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder29"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;assignees&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder30"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;assignee&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;orgname&gt;</span><span>Renesas Mobile Corporation</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/orgname&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;role&gt;</span><span>03</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/role&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/assignee&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/assignees&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-bibliographic-data-application&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder31"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;abstract<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">abstract</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0000</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>A user equipment UE receives from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells/frequencies, and at least one individual neighbor cell/frequency supports a plurality of frequency bands. The neighbor cells/frequencies are filtered to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or frequency bands which are also supported by the UE. Examples are given of various system information blocks for sending the frequency band indications to the UE. In one embodiment they are arranged in an information element IE having an entry for each of the neighbor cells/frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry. In another the IE has an index and an associated frequency band(s) where a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells/frequencies referred to by the index belong to the associated frequency band(s).</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/abstract&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder32"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;drawings<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder33"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00000</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00000</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00000</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">198.97mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">178.22mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00000.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder34"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">223.10mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">179.24mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">orientation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">landscape</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00001.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder35"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">218.61mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">158.41mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">orientation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">landscape</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00002.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder36"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00003</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">214.63mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">177.55mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00003.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder37"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00004</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">235.46mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">192.19mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00004.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder38"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00005</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">252.81mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">191.01mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">orientation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">landscape</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20130078989A1-20130328-D00005.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/drawings&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder39"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;description<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">description</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>TECHNICAL FIELD</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The exemplary and non-limiting embodiments of this invention relate generally to wireless communication systems, methods, devices and computer programs and, more specifically, relate to neighbor cells which support multiple frequency bands.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>BACKGROUND</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0002</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The following abbreviations that may be found in the specification and/or the drawing figures are defined as follows:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder40"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0000</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder41"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;tables<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">TABLE-US-00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder42"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;table<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">frame</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">none</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">rowsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder43"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;tgroup<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">left</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">rowsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">cols</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">3</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;colspec<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colname</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">offset</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colwidth</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">14pt</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">left</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;colspec<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colname</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colwidth</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">42pt</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">left</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;colspec<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colname</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">2</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">colwidth</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">161pt</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">left</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder44"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;thead&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder45"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">namest</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">offset</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">nameend</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">2</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">center</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">rowsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/thead&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder46"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;tbody<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">valign</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">top</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder47"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>3GPP</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>third generation partnership project</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder48"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>EARFCN</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>EUTRA absolute radio frequency channel number</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder49"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>EUTRA</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>evolved universal terrestrial radio access</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder50"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>IE</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>information element</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder51"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>LTE</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>long term evolution (EUTRA network)</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder52"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>LTE-A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>LTE-advanced</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder53"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>RAN</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>radio access network</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder54"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>RF</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>radiofrequency</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder55"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>SI</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>system information</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder56"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>SIB</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>system information block</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder57"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>UARFCN</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>UTRA absolute radio frequency channel number</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder58"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>UMTS</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>universal mobile telecommunication system</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder59"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>UE</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry&gt;</span><span>user equipment</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/entry&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder60"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;row&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;entry<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">namest</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">offset</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">nameend</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">2</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">align</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">center</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">rowsep</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/row&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/tbody&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/tgroup&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/table&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/tables&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0003</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Cellular radio communications now include individual cells operating on multiple radio frequency channels in order to better support a variety of different UEs, some of which may be capable of operating on only one of these frequency bands which is different than a band for which another UE in the cell is capable. Additionally, some bands in use by one cell may have some frequency portion overlapping with bands in an adjacent neighbor cell, particularly where such neighbor cells operate under different radio access technologies such as UMTS and LTE. For example, in the HSPA version of UMTS bands II and XXV have respective frequency bands 1930-1990 MHz and 1930-1995 MHz and thus are overlapping in frequency. There is a similar overlap among bands V (869-894 MHz), VI (875-885 MHz) and new band XXVI (814-849 and 859-894 MHz); bands IV (2110-2115 MHz) and X (2110-2170 MHz); and bands III (1805-1880 MHz) and IX (1844.9-1879.9 MHz).</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder61"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0004</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Relevant to the above scenarios are certain proposals for LTE Release 10 set forth in document R2-114158 by Qualcomm entitled MULTIPLE HARMONISED BANDS PER CELL and in document R2-114299 by Ericsson and ST-Ericsson entitled MULTIPLE FREQUENCY BAND INDICATORS IN A CELL (both from 3GPP TSG-RAN WG2 meeting #75; Athens, Greece; 22-26 Aug. 2011). Specifically, these documents propose that some cells which belong to a frequency in an overlapping band will broadcast the multiple bands they support according to variously named extension fields for the SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. In the examples given there are in the context of a new band </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> which was recently introduced into Release 10 discussions. This broadcast that multiple bands are supported is to allow new UEs which support the new band </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to relax their RF requirements as compared to the older defined bands so that when roaming onto an operators band they may then apply the new relaxed requirements, and thereby avoid the UE having to perform interoperability testing (IOT). These proposals are to additionally allow older UEs supporting the older bands to camp on the same cell as well as to allow legacy UEs to camp on the newer band. These proposals seek to adapt the requirement at section 5.4 of 3GPP TS 25.101 v10.2.0 (2011-06) that a cell is allowed to indicate in SI only one frequency band it supports.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder62"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0005</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>A problem arises in the above solutions when considering UE mobility between cells. A UE performs mobility based on a neighbor list given to it by SI. The conventional practice is that for UMTS the individual cells on each frequency are listed, and for LTE only the frequency is listed. But if the above proposals of introducing multiple bands support in a cell were adopted, the UE would not know whether the neighbor cell (UMTS) or neighbor frequency (LTE) belongs to a frequency band which the UE supports until after that UE reads SI from the target cell (specifically, SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> if the target cell is UMTS and SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> if the target cell is LTE). So in some cases the UE will give up on re-selecting to the neighbor cell because of a non-supported frequency band only after the UE performed some mobility related processes (such as neighbor cell measurement, cell quality evaluation, cell reselection, target cell SI reading), which depletes the battery or other portable power source of the UE. Since the UARFCN or EARFCN indicated in the neighbor cell/frequency list may belong to multiple bands, the UE cannot determine which band to which it refers.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0008</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0006</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Further, the serving cell's broadcast of its own UARFCN/EARFCN referring to a specific frequency can be different for a different band; different UARFCN/EARFCN can refer to the same frequency but in a different band/channel. In this case the neighbor cell/frequency list which the UE uses for mobility purposes would need to be updated to broadcast the same frequency multiple times so that all UEs can reselect. But this then causes a problem in that there is a limited number of cells which can be broadcast in the UTRAN neighbor cell list. Even in some of today's networks, the size limitation imposed but the signalling restrictions of the UTRAN neighbor cell list can restrict the neighbor cell configuration therefore increasing the size further is not practical. This also causes a problem due to there being a maximum number of frequencies in UTRAN and/or EUTRAN which the UE which is required to measure. In UMTS the UE is required to be able to measure two frequencies in addition to the carrier (serving cell) frequency, and in LTE the UE is required to measure three frequencies in addition to the carrier frequency. If for example the serving cell supports three bands, the neighbor cell/frequency list size may increase by a factor of three. In principle the UE could measure three bands if the frequencies are all identical, but this is not required by current radio specifications because currently there is no possibility for a cell to belong to more than one band.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0009</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>For that reason this issue was not a concern in the past. While there were some overlapping frequency bands (for example, Band V and Band VI overlap) there was no practical situation that the Band V cell could be signalled as a neighbor cell of a Band VI serving cell and additionally there was no possibility for either the serving or neighbor cell to support multiple bands. The detailed teachings below resolve the above problem which is wasteful of the UE's limited power source.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>SUMMARY</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0010</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0008</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The foregoing and other problems are overcome, and other advantages are realized, by the use of the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0011</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0009</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a first exemplary embodiment of the invention there is an apparatus comprising at least one processor; and at least one memory including computer program code. In this embodiment the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to: receive from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and filter the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0012</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0010</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a second exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a method comprising: receiving from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0013</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0011</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a third exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a computer readable memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor. In this embodiment the computer program comprises code for receiving in system information broadcast by a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and code for filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0014</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0012</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a fourth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is an apparatus comprising at least one processor; and at least one memory including computer program code. In this embodiment the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to: obtain frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and send to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0015</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a fifth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a method comprising: obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0016</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0014</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In a sixth exemplary embodiment of the invention there is a computer readable memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor. In this embodiment the computer program comprises code for obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and code for sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder63"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;description-of-drawings&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder64"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0017</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0015</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is a plan view of a conceptual radio environment in which the various exemplary embodiments detailed herein may be practiced to advantage.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder65"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0018</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0016</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is an exemplary signaling diagram showing signaling and internal processes according to exemplary embodiments detailed herein.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder66"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0019</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0017</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is a logic flow diagram illustrating from the perspective of the UE the operation of a method, and a result of execution of computer program instructions embodied on a computer readable memory, for practicing exemplary embodiments of these teachings.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder67"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0020</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0018</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is a logic flow diagram illustrating from the perspective of the serving cell/serving access node the operation of a method, and a result of execution of computer program instructions embodied on a computer readable memory, for practicing exemplary embodiments of these teachings.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder68"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0021</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0019</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is a simplified block diagram of some of the devices shown at </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> which are exemplary electronic devices suitable for use in practicing the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/description-of-drawings&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0022</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0020</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>While the two documents noted in the background section above refer to the cell broadcasting in its own SI the additional bands which it supports, those proposals do not go far enough. To avoid the UE undertaking certain mobility procedures as noted above which will in the end prove fruitless due to the UE's incompatibility with a neighbor cell, in an embodiment of these teachings the serving cell will broadcast in its SI an indication of the multiple frequency bands that its individual neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies support. For example, a UTRAN serving cell will broadcast in its own SI indications of the frequency bands which its neighbor UTRAN cells support and which its neighbor LTE frequencies support. For the case of a LTE serving cell it will broadcast in its own SI indications of the frequency bands which its neighbor frequencies (UTRAN and LTE) support. In this manner the UE can see the entire list of bands which each neighbor cell or frequency supports, and construct its own locally stored neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list (which it uses for its mobility choices) by filtering according to the UE's own capabilities on those channels/bands. Since the UE will have the relevant information before reading SI of the neighbor cell it can avoid performing mobility-related processes directed toward cell reselection to a neighbor cell to which it is incompatible. In case a network does not update the neighbor cell or frequency list the UE can still use the frequency band information in its previously-defined filtered list to avoid performing measurements in preparation for handover in a particular radio access technology. In these teachings a new cell which belongs to more than one frequency band can broadcast in the neighbor cell or frequency list that another cell or frequency also belongs to more than one frequency band, such as by indicating the frequency bands in the neighbors' UARFCN and/or EARFCN (depending on whether the neighbor cell is a UMTS or a LTE cell).</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder69"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0023</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0021</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Before detailing further specific implementations, reference is made to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> for illustrating an exemplary radio environment in which these teachings can be practiced to advantage. There is a UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> operating in the vicinity of a serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and there are multiple neighbor cells operating on multiple neighbor frequencies, of which neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is exemplary. The specifics vary depending on whether the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> are operating in the UMTS or the LTE systems, but in general the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will broadcast in its system information indications about all of the frequency bands which the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies support. The UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will of course get the SI broadcast from the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> prior to performing any mobility-related procedures toward a given neighbor cell or neighbor frequency. From the list of frequency bands for the neighbor cells/frequencies the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will determine which if any of those bands it supports. The UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will then construct the neighbor cell list using all the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies it learned from the SI of its serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, excluding those the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> does not support. When the UE needs to perform some neighbor cell measurement, cell reselection, or other mobility-related process, it will use only those channels on the neighbor cell list that it constructed by filtering using the UE's own capabilities, and so all neighbor cells and frequencies on the UE's locally stored list will be viable to use for cell reselection (assuming sufficient signal strength and other dynamic parameters of the radio environment).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder70"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0024</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0022</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> is an exemplary signaling diagram illustrating signaling and internal processes in the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> according to the above overview. At </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>202</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> broadcasts its SI, which according to these teachings includes the frequency band information for the UARFCN and/or the EARFCN of each of its neighbor cells/frequencies. At </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>204</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, having received the serving cell's broadcast SI </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>202</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, then filters all of those neighbor cells/frequencies according to the UE's own frequency band capabilities. Each band the UE supports gets filtered in and each band it does not gets filtered out. In one embodiment the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> constructs its neighbor cell list with this filtering and stores it in its local memory for use in the cell. That neighbor cell list will include every neighbor cell frequency band that the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> learned from the serving cell's SI </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>202</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, as filtered at </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>204</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to exclude all bands which the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> does not support. If for example a particular neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is assigned to only one frequency band according to the serving cell's SI </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>202</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and if the UE does not support the frequency band, then the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can exclude the cell from its neighbor cell list. If for example the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> supports three frequency bands which the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> learns at </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>202</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> from the serving cell's SI and the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> supports two of them, then the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will include the cell into the neighbor cell list, and it keeps those two frequency bands in its memory. The UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> uses the neighbor cell list to select which cells/frequencies to measure and re-select on. The reader will recognize that typically there will be multiple neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies whose frequency band or bands (as the case may be) are indicated by the SI of the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder71"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0025</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0023</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In another embodiment the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> stores the list it receives from the network, and filters at block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>204</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> on a case by case basis anytime the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is about to start a mobility related procedure, and continues that procedure only if the band relevant to the procedure passes the UE-capability filtering. In this embodiment the UE does not store the filtered list but runs a stored algorithm that filters the network-supplied list each time it's needed and the same result is obtained. However the filtering of block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>204</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is implemented, at </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>206</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the UE uses only the neighbor cells/frequencies which are indicated to support a frequency band which is also supported by the UE itself for any mobility related procedure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder72"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0026</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0024</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>From the network perspective, if the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is a UMTS cell the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> signals the frequency band information for the UARFCN of that UMTS neighbor cell in the system information broadcasted on the serving cell's broadcast control channel. If the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is an LTE cell the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> signals the frequency band information for the EARFCN of the neighbor frequencies in the serving cell's system information. In case the frequency is associated with different bands, the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will signal all of the potential bands that can be found on that frequency.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder73"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0027</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0025</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>From the UE's perspective, the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will collect all of the neighbor cells' associated frequency bands signaled in the serving cell's SI. For those neighbor cells which are UMTS cells the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> checks that neighbor cell's frequency band information before performing any mobility procedures to that neighbor cell. For a neighbor cell for which all of its assigned frequency bands are not supported by the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> simply discards the UTRAN neighbor cell from its locally stored list. That is, the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> will not attempt any mobility procedure to move to that neighbor UMTS cell whose frequency band or frequency bands the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> does not support. For a neighbor UMTS cell whose frequency band the UE does support, the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may perform the necessary mobility procedures for that neighbor UMTS cell (assuming it is a good cell reselection candidate in other respects such as signal strength).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder74"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0028</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0026</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Again from the UE's perspective, for those neighbor frequencies which are associated with LTE cells the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> simply does not attempt to measure or perform any mobility procedures on that frequency if the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> does not support the frequency bands indicated in the serving cell's SI. This is similar to the UMTS cell procedure except that the LTE cell frequency band information is always given per frequency instead of per cell. There may be cases where there is a mixture of different frequency band cells on one frequency. To address that case the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can signal in its SI the cell PCI range, a list of each frequency band on a cell or frequency, in order to optimize the UE mobility/reselection attempts. This case is expected to be atypical and likely not even needed due to the increased signalling overhead in SI it represents.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder75"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0029</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0027</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>There are multiple ways to implement this increased signaling in the serving cell's SI. The following examples do so by adding an information element to the serving cell's system information which includes a list of frequency band information for all the neighbor cells and neighbor frequencies which support more than one frequency band. For example, if the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is UMTS it can add that new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band UMTS neighbor cell(s) in the serving cell's system information block type </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>) or system information block type </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis (SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis) or possibly its system information block type </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>), and can also add that new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band LTE neighbor frequencies in its system information block type </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>). If the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is LTE it can add the new IE which carries the band information for its multi-band LTE neighbor frequencies in the serving cell's system information block type </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>). The number of entries in this new IE is the same as the number of neighbor cells for UMTS and the number of neighbor frequencies for LTE. Each entry indicates the frequency band(s) associated with the corresponding neighbor cell or neighbor frequency in the neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list. When the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> filters the network supplied neighbor cell list or neighbor frequency list, the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> excludes the cells/frequencies not belonging to the UE supported frequency bands. Then the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> performs cell reselection only on the filtered neighbor cell list or the filtered neighbor frequency list.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder76"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0030</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0028</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In another embodiment the IE is added by the UMTS serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to its SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> or SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis (and possibly also its SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>) for the UMTS neighbor cells and in its SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> for its LTE neighbor frequencies. Or if the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is an LTE cell it can add the new IE to its SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> for all its neighbor frequencies. In these embodiments the IE can indicate an index and one or more frequency bands for each neighbor cell/frequency. The index, X for example, would indicate that the neighbor cells/frequencies from the 1</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;sup&gt;</span><span>st </span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/sup&gt;</span></div><span>neighbor cell/frequency to the X</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;sup&gt;</span><span>th </span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/sup&gt;</span></div><span>neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list belong to the frequency band(s) signalled in the same new IE. If more than one new IE is included in the SIB, then the subsequent IE's index, Y for example, would indicate that the neighbor cells/frequencies from (the previous IE's index +1)</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;sup&gt;</span><span>th </span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/sup&gt;</span></div><span>neighbor cell/frequency to the Y</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;sup&gt;</span><span>th </span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/sup&gt;</span></div><span>neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list belong to the frequency band(s) signalled in the same IE. This can be repeated for additional indices. The UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> would then filter and exclude as in the above paragraph and perform cell reselection using its filtered neighbor cell/frequency list.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder77"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0031</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0029</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In another embodiment instead of a new IE in an existing SIB the information on the neighbor cell frequency bands is informed to the UE's via a new SIB, for example SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>21</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> in the case of UMTS cells and SIB</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> in the case of LTE frequencies. Including the IE similar to that noted above in one or both of these new SIBs is a simple way to present the frequency band information to the UEs. In one implementation there is one entry in this new IE for each of the neighbor cells/frequencies, and each entry indicates the frequency band(s) associated with the corresponding neighbor cell/frequency in the neighbor cell/frequency list. In another implementation the IE indicates the index and the frequency band(s) for each neighbor cell/frequency as detailed above.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder78"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0032</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0030</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>One technical effect of these teachings is that the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can identify from its serving cell SI which neighbor cells/frequencies, including all cells/frequencies on a frequency band, can be considered as a candidate suitable cell/frequency for cell reselection before performing any mobility procedures. This saves on UE battery consumption as noted in the background section above. Relatedly, implementing these teachings are seen to result in more effective cell reselection by the UE since there will be fewer failed/aborted cell reselections.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0033</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0031</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>On the network side one technical effect is that the network operator can deploy multiple harmonized band cells without affecting UE battery life. The size of the neighbor cell/frequency list is unaffected, and so there is no need to utilize additional entries to refer to the same cell since the additional frequency band information can extend the applicability of a single UARFCN/EARFCN to refer to multiple bands. For this reason implementation of these teachings is not seen to affect the stipulated performance requirements.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder79"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0034</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0032</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIGS. 3-4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> are logic flow diagrams which may each be considered to illustrate the operation of a method, and a result of execution of a computer program stored in a computer readable memory, and a specific manner in which components of an electronic device are configured to cause that electronic device to operate. The various blocks shown in each of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIGS. 3-4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> may also be considered as a plurality of coupled logic circuit elements constructed to carry out the associated function(s), or specific result of strings of computer program code stored in a memory.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0035</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0033</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Such blocks and the functions they represent are non-limiting examples, and may be practiced in various components such as integrated circuit chips and modules, and that the exemplary embodiments of this invention may be realized in an apparatus that is embodied as an integrated circuit. The integrated circuit, or circuits, may comprise circuitry (as well as possibly firmware) for embodying at least one or more of a data processor or data processors, a digital signal processor or processors, baseband circuitry and radio frequency circuitry that are configurable so as to operate in accordance with the exemplary embodiments of this invention.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder80"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0036</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0034</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> details particular exemplary embodiments of the invention from the perspective of the UE. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> may be implemented by the entire UE or by one or more components thereof, more generally termed an apparatus. At block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>302</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> the UE receives from its serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported. At block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>304</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> filters the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by the UE itself. As in the above examples the UE may filter to generate a new list which it stores in its local memory and checks each time it needs to run a mobility procedure on a new band, or it may store the network-provided neighbor cell/frequency list and filter out those which only support a band or bands for which the UE is not capable on an as needed basis when checking each new neighbor cell/frequency for a mobility related procedure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder81"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0037</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0035</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Further portions of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> are optional and may or may not be combined with one another in various embodiments. Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>306</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> details that the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell and the at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell. Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>308</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> specifies that the system information comprises at least one of system information block types </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> as detailed in the examples above.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder82"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0038</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0036</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>310</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> specifies one embodiment of the IE above, that the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry. Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>312</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> specifies another embodiment of the IE above, that the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index (X) indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells/frequencies referred to by the index (1</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;sup&gt;</span><span>st </span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/sup&gt;</span></div><span>through the Xth) belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index. There can of course be more than one index in the IE of this embodiment with different indices referring to a different plurality of neighbor cells/frequencies and associated with a different band or bands.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder83"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0039</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0037</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>From the above description and examples, the UE functioning according to the </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> embodiment is configured to utilize that filtered neighbor cell/neighbor frequency list for its own cell reselection processes.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder84"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0040</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0038</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> details particular exemplary embodiments of the invention from the perspective of the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> which sends its SI with all of the neighbor cells' or neighbor frequencys' associated frequency bands. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> may be implemented by the entire serving cell (more generally a wireless network access node) or by one or more components thereof, which is also more generally termed an apparatus. At block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>402</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> the serving cell obtains frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or neighbor frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands. The serving cell may determine this band information itself such as by collecting that information from the neighbor cells directly via an X2 or similar interface, or the neighbor cells and associated frequency bands may be obtained from a higher network node such as a radio network controller or mobility management entity. At block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>402</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the ‘individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency’ is used to better specify that from among the whole neighbor cell/frequency list the serving cell compiles, there is at least one of them which supports multiple frequency bands since not all of the neighbor cells/frequencies may be multi-band capable. However the serving cell obtains this frequency band data, it then at block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>404</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> sends to UEs indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder85"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0041</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0039</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Further portions of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> are optional and may or may not be combined with one another in various embodiments. Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>406</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> states as with the above exemplary examples that the indications are sent to the UEs in system information broadcast by the serving cell, and the at least one individual neighbor cell/neighbor frequency is a neighbor cell/frequency to the serving cell. Block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>408</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> recites the SIBs from the above examples: the indications are added to at least one of system information block types </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder86"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0042</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0040</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Blocks </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>410</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>412</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> give the different embodiments of the new IE that are detailed above. At block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>410</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> the serving cell sends the indications of block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>404</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> by first arranging the indications in an IE having an entry for each of the neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry, and then sends the IE in SI. The other embodiment from the above examples is at block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>412</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, the sending of block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>404</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is implemented by the serving cell first arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies that are referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and then the serving cell sends this IE in its SI.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder87"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0043</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0041</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Reference is now made to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> for illustrating a simplified block diagram of various electronic devices and apparatus that are suitable for use in practicing the exemplary embodiments of this invention. In </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIG. 5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span> there is a serving cell/serving network access node </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and a neighbor cell/neighbor network access node </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, which are adapted for communication over respective wireless links </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>21</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>23</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> with an apparatus </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> such as mobile terminals or termed more generally as a user equipment UE. In certain networks such as LTE there is also an interface </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>27</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> between the serving </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and neighbor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> cell. The illustrated neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> stands in the place of the ‘at least one individual neighbor cell or neighbor frequency’ noted above for </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>FIGS. 3-4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div><span>, but there are typically other neighbor cells/frequencies to the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> some or all of which may also support multiple frequency bands. The serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be further communicatively coupled via link </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>25</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to a higher network node </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> such as a mobility management entity/serving gateway MME/S-GW </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> in the case of the LTE system or a radio network controller in the case of the UMTS system.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder88"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0044</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0042</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> includes processing means such as at least one data processor (DP) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, storing means such as at least one computer-readable memory (MEM) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B storing at least one computer program (PROG) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, communicating means such as a transmitter TX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D and a receiver RX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E for bidirectional wireless communications with the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and with the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> via one or more antennas </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>F. Within the memory </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B of the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> but shown separately as reference number </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>G is also a computer program for filtering, according to the UE capabilities, the list of neighbor cells/neighbor frequencies which the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> receives from the serving cell's system information as is detailed above in various embodiments.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder89"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0045</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0043</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> also includes processing means such as at least one data processor (DP) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, storing means such as at least one computer-readable memory (MEM) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B storing at least one computer program (PROG) </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, and communicating means such as a transmitter TX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D and a receiver RX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E for bidirectional wireless communications with its associated user devices </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> via one or more antennas </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>F and a modem. The serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> also has stored in its memory at </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>G software to assemble in its system information broadcasts all of the neighbor cells/frequencies and all of their associated frequency bands as is detailed by example above. The serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is similarly functional with blocks </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>F, but its block </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>G simply has its own multi-channel capability which the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> learns via the interface </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>27</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (if the LTE system) or via the higher network node </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>/radio network controller (if a UMTS system). But note that the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> has the same functionality according to these teachings as the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> which it uses when sending its own SI to its UEs. By example, the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be a node B (UMTS) or an e-NodeB (LTE), the neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be a node B (UMTS) or an e-NodeB (LTE), and in the case of the LTE system the interface </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>27</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be an X2 interface between them.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder90"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0046</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0044</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>For completeness the higher network node </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is also shown to include a DP </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, and a MEM </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B storing a PROG </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, and additionally a modem </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>24</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>H for communicating with at least the serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> (to show embodiments in which the neighbor cell is not under the same higher network node). While not particularly illustrated for the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> or cells </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, those devices are also assumed to include as part of their wireless communicating means a modem which may in one exemplary but non limiting embodiment be inbuilt on an RF front end chip so as to carry the respective TX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D/</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D/</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>D and RX </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E/</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E/</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>E.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder91"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0047</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0045</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>At least one of the PROGs </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C in the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and in the serving and neighbor cells </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is assumed to include program instructions that, when executed by the associated DP </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, enable the device to operate in accordance with the exemplary embodiments of this invention as detailed more fully above. In this regard the exemplary embodiments of this invention may be implemented at least in part by computer software stored on the MEM </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B which is executable by the DP </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A of the respective devices </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>; or by hardware; or by a combination of tangibly stored software and hardware (and tangibly stored firmware). Electronic devices implementing these aspects of the invention need not be the entire UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, or serving cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, or neighbor cell </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, but exemplary embodiments may be implemented by one or more components of same such as the above described tangibly stored software, hardware, firmware and DP, or a system on a chip SOC or an application specific integrated circuit ASIC or a digital signal processor DSP or a modem or a subscriber identity module commonly referred to as a SIM card.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder92"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0048</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0046</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Various embodiments of the UE </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can include, but are not limited to: cellular telephones; data cards, USB dongles, personal portable digital devices having wireless communication capabilities including but not limited to laptop/palmtop/tablet computers, digital cameras and music devices, and Internet appliances.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder93"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0049</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0047</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Various embodiments of the computer readable MEM </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B include any data storage technology type which is suitable to the local technical environment, including but not limited to semiconductor based memory devices, magnetic memory devices and systems, optical memory devices and systems, fixed memory, removable memory, disc memory, flash memory, DRAM, SRAM, EEPROM and the like. Various embodiments of the DP </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>26</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A include but are not limited to general purpose computers, special purpose computers, microprocessors, digital signal processors (DSPs) and multi-core processors.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0050</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0048</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Various modifications and adaptations to the foregoing exemplary embodiments of this invention may become apparent to those skilled in the relevant arts in view of the foregoing description. While the exemplary embodiments have been described above in the context of the UMTS and LTE/LTE-A systems, it should be appreciated that the exemplary embodiments of this invention are not limited for use with only this one particular type of wireless communication system, and that they may be used to advantage in other wireless communication systems such as for example WCDMA and others which may interface with a neighbor cell that supports multiple frequency bands.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0051</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0049</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Some of the various features of the above non-limiting embodiments may be used to advantage without the corresponding use of other described features. The foregoing description should therefore be considered as merely illustrative of the principles, teachings and exemplary embodiments of this invention, and not in limitation thereof.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/description&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder94"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claims<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">claims</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder95"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder96"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. An apparatus comprising at least one processor; and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>at least one memory including computer program code;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>receive from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>filter the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or frequency bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder97"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder98"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell and the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder99"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00003</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder100"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the system information comprises at least one of system information block types </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder101"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00004</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder102"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder103"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00005</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder104"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder105"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00006</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder106"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>6</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the apparatus comprises the user equipment which is configured to utilize only the filtered neighbor cells or frequencies for cell reselection.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder107"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder108"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A method, comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>receiving from a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>filtering the neighbor cells or frequencies to retain only those which are indicated to support a frequency band or bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder109"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00008</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00008</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder110"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>8</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the indications are received in system information broadcast by the serving cell.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder111"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00009</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00009</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder112"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>9</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder113"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00010</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00010</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder114"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder115"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00011</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00011</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder116"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor, in which the computer program comprises:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>code for receiving in system information broadcast by a serving cell indications of frequency bands supported by neighbor cells, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell for which there is indicated a plurality of frequency bands supported; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>code for filtering the frequency bands to retain only those indicated frequency bands which are also supported by a user equipment.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder117"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00012</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00012</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder118"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The memory according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00011</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells and a list of frequency bands for each entry.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder119"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder120"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The memory according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00011</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the received indications are arranged in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder121"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00014</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00014</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder122"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. An apparatus comprising
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>at least one processor; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>at least one memory including computer program code;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured, with the at least one processor, to cause the apparatus at least to:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtain frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>send to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder123"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00015</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00015</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder124"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>15</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00014</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the indications are sent to the user equipments in system information broadcast by the apparatus which comprises a serving cell, and the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency is a neighbor cell or frequency to the serving cell.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder125"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00016</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00016</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder126"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>16</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00015</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 15</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the system information comprises at least one of system information block types </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>bis, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder127"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00017</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00017</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder128"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>17</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00014</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured with the at least one processor to cause the apparatus to send to the user equipments the indications by:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>arranging the indications in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>sending the information element in system information.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder129"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00018</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00018</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder130"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>18</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The apparatus according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00014</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the at least one memory and the computer program code is configured with the at least one processor to cause the apparatus to send to the user equipments the indications by:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>sending the information element in system information.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder131"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00019</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00019</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder132"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A method comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder133"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00020</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00020</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder134"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00019</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which the indications are sent to the user equipments in broadcast system information, and the at least one individual neighbor cell is an neighbor cell or frequency to a serving cell executing the method.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder135"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00021</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00021</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder136"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>21</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00019</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which sending to the user equipments the indications comprises:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>arranging the indications in an information element having an entry for each of the neighbor cells or frequencies and a list of frequency bands for each entry; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>sending the information element in system information.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder137"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00022</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00022</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder138"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The method according to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00019</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span> or </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00020</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>20</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, in which sending to the user equipments the indications comprises:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>arranging the indications in an information element having an index and one or more associated frequency bands, in which a value of the index indicates that one or more of the neighbor cells or frequencies referred to by the index belong to the one or more frequency bands associated with the index; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>sending the information element in system information.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder139"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00023</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00023</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder140"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>23</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A memory tangibly storing a computer program that is executable by at least one processor, in which the computer program comprises:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>code for obtaining frequency bands supported by neighbor cells or frequencies, in which there is at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency which supports a plurality of frequency bands; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>code for sending to user equipments indications of the frequency bands associated with the respective neighbor cells or frequencies that support them, including the plurality of frequency bands supported by the at least one individual neighbor cell or frequency.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claims&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-patent-application&gt;</span></div></div></div></body></html>