<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"><head><style id="xml-viewer-style">/* Copyright 2014 The Chromium Authors
 * Use of this source code is governed by a BSD-style license that can be
 * found in the LICENSE file.
 */

:root {
  color-scheme: light dark;
}

div.header {
    border-bottom: 2px solid black;
    padding-bottom: 5px;
    margin: 10px;
}

@media (prefers-color-scheme: dark) {
  div.header {
    border-bottom: 2px solid white;
  }
}

div.folder &gt; div.hidden {
    display:none;
}

div.folder &gt; span.hidden {
    display:none;
}

.pretty-print {
    margin-top: 1em;
    margin-left: 20px;
    font-family: monospace;
    font-size: 13px;
}

#webkit-xml-viewer-source-xml {
    display: none;
}

.opened {
    margin-left: 1em;
}

.comment {
    white-space: pre;
}

.folder-button {
    user-select: none;
    cursor: pointer;
    display: inline-block;
    margin-left: -10px;
    width: 10px;
    background-repeat: no-repeat;
    background-position: left top;
    vertical-align: bottom;
}

.fold {
    background: url("data:image/svg+xml,&lt;svg xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' fill='%23909090' width='10' height='10'&gt;&lt;path d='M0 0 L8 0 L4 7 Z'/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;");
    height: 10px;
}

.open {
    background: url("data:image/svg+xml,&lt;svg xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2000/svg' fill='%23909090' width='10' height='10'&gt;&lt;path d='M0 0 L0 8 L7 4 Z'/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;");
    height: 10px;
}
</style></head><body><div id="webkit-xml-viewer-source-xml"><us-patent-application xmlns="" lang="EN" dtd-version="v4.6 2022-02-17" file="US20230368518A1-20231116.XML" status="PRODUCTION" id="us-patent-application" country="US" date-produced="20231101" date-publ="20231116">
<us-bibliographic-data-application lang="EN" country="US">
<publication-reference>
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>20230368518</doc-number>
<kind>A1</kind>
<date>20231116</date>
</document-id>
</publication-reference>
<application-reference appl-type="utility">
<document-id>
<country>US</country>
<doc-number>18197891</doc-number>
<date>20230516</date>
</document-id>
</application-reference>
<us-application-series-code>18</us-application-series-code>
<priority-claims>
<priority-claim sequence="01" kind="national">
<country>KR</country>
<doc-number>10-2022-0059423</doc-number>
<date>20220516</date>
</priority-claim>
</priority-claims>
<classifications-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>94</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>77</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>82</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
<classification-ipcr>
<ipc-version-indicator><date>20060101</date></ipc-version-indicator>
<classification-level>A</classification-level>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>774</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
</classification-ipcr>
</classifications-ipcr>
<classifications-cpc>
<main-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20220101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>94</subgroup>
<symbol-position>F</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</main-cpc>
<further-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20220101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>7715</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20220101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>82</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
<classification-cpc>
<cpc-version-indicator><date>20220101</date></cpc-version-indicator>
<section>G</section>
<class>06</class>
<subclass>V</subclass>
<main-group>10</main-group>
<subgroup>774</subgroup>
<symbol-position>L</symbol-position>
<classification-value>I</classification-value>
<action-date><date>20231116</date></action-date>
<generating-office><country>US</country></generating-office>
<classification-status>B</classification-status>
<classification-data-source>H</classification-data-source>
<scheme-origination-code>C</scheme-origination-code>
</classification-cpc>
</further-cpc>
</classifications-cpc>
<invention-title id="d2e61">DEEP NEURAL NETWORK-BASED OBJECT DETECTION METHOD, AND CLOUD SEVER AND EDGE DEVICE PERFORMING DEEP NEURAL NETWORK-BASED OBJECT DETECTION METHOD</invention-title>
<us-parties>
<us-applicants>
<us-applicant sequence="00" app-type="applicant" designation="us-only" applicant-authority-category="assignee">
<addressbook>
<orgname>Research &amp; Business Foundation SUNGKYUNKWAN UNIVERSITY</orgname>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
<residence>
<country>KR</country>
</residence>
</us-applicant>
</us-applicants>
<inventors>
<inventor sequence="00" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>LEE</last-name>
<first-name>Joo Chan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
<inventor sequence="01" designation="us-only">
<addressbook>
<last-name>KO</last-name>
<first-name>Jong Hwan</first-name>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</inventor>
</inventors>
</us-parties>
<assignees>
<assignee>
<addressbook>
<orgname>Research &amp; Business Foundation SUNGKYUNKWAN UNIVERSITY</orgname>
<role>03</role>
<address>
<city>Suwon-si</city>
<country>KR</country>
</address>
</addressbook>
</assignee>
</assignees>
</us-bibliographic-data-application>
<abstract id="abstract">
<p id="p-0001" num="0000">The present disclosure relates to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method, and more particularly, to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object in an image in real time.</p>
</abstract>
<drawings id="DRAWINGS">
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00000" num="00000">
<img id="EMI-D00000" he="138.35mm" wi="108.54mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00000.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00001" num="00001">
<img id="EMI-D00001" he="129.20mm" wi="151.72mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00001.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00002" num="00002">
<img id="EMI-D00002" he="178.39mm" wi="122.34mm" orientation="landscape" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00002.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00003" num="00003">
<img id="EMI-D00003" he="138.35mm" wi="135.81mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00003.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00004" num="00004">
<img id="EMI-D00004" he="160.27mm" wi="151.38mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00004.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00005" num="00005">
<img id="EMI-D00005" he="175.18mm" wi="130.39mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00005.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00006" num="00006">
<img id="EMI-D00006" he="126.32mm" wi="158.83mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00006.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
<figure id="Fig-EMI-D00007" num="00007">
<img id="EMI-D00007" he="179.92mm" wi="110.57mm" file="US20230368518A1-20231116-D00007.TIF" alt="embedded image" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/>
</figure>
</drawings>
<description id="description">
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0001" level="1">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading>
<p id="p-0002" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method, and more particularly, to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object in an image in real time. This work was supported by Institute of Information &amp; communications Technology Planning &amp; Evaluation (IITP) grant funded by Korea government (MSIT) ([Project unique No.: 1711126132; Project No.: 2019-0-00421-003; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Artificial Intelligence Graduate School Program], [Project unique No.: 1711139517; Project No.: 2021-0-02068-001; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Development for Artificial Intelligence Innovative Hub], and [Project unique No.: 1711139247; Project No.: 2021-0-02052-001; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Development for Artificial Intelligence System on a Chip for Smart Mobility]).</p>
<heading id="h-0002" level="1">BACKGROUND</heading>
<p id="p-0003" num="0002">With the recent development of deep neural networks (DNNs), excellent performance has been implemented in various tasks related to computer vision. However, due to resource constraints, it is still difficult for edge devices to acquire images in real time and perform real-time inference of DNN models with complex deep neural networks. In this case, images obtained by an edge device can be transmitted to a cloud sever equipped with a high-performance GPU for processing. However, due to the characteristics of an edge device that needs to use a wireless network, it may take a long time to transmit images. In order to solve this problem, it is possible to use an edge-cloud split inference technique in which an edge device uses a part of a deep neural network, and features smaller than the original image are transmitted to a cloud sever for processing.</p>
<p id="p-0004" num="0003">In general, since the size of a feature decreases as the number of layers for extracting a feature increases, an appropriate split point needs to be present for each network.</p>
<p id="p-0005" num="0004">However, unlike image classifiers, general deep neural network-based object detectors need to use multiple layers of features in order to effectively detect objects of various sizes.</p>
<p id="p-0006" num="0005">That is, object detection is not performed using only the last feature of a feature-extracting layer, but predetermined intermediate features among a plurality of feature-extracting layers are also required.</p>
<p id="p-0007" num="0006">For this reason, the amount of transmission increases in a split inference situation, and thus it is difficult to find an appropriate split point in a general object detector layer.</p>
<heading id="h-0003" level="1">SUMMARY</heading>
<p id="p-0008" num="0007">In view of the above, the present disclosure provides a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object of an image in real time.</p>
<p id="p-0009" num="0008">Objects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned object, and other objects not mentioned will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the description below.</p>
<p id="p-0010" num="0009">The aspects of the present disclosure are not limited to the foregoing, and other aspects not mentioned herein will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the following description.</p>
<p id="p-0011" num="0010">In accordance with an aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a cloud sever for detecting an object of an image based on a single feature received from an edge device, the cloud sever may comprise: a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a pre-trained reconstructor of the cloud sever; and a processor, wherein the processor is configured to: receive a single feature of an image from the edge device, wherein the edge device includes an extractor having a plurality of layers and the single feature of the image is extracted by a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device; and obtain an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature received from the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever, and detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature obtained from the extractor of the cloud sever to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0012" num="0011">The extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</p>
<p id="p-0013" num="0012">The reconstructor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0014" num="0013">Each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0015" num="0014">A number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0016" num="0015">A number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0017" num="0016">In accordance with another aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided an edge device for transmitting a single feature obtained from an image to a cloud sever, the cloud sever may comprise: a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the edge device having a plurality of layers; and a processor, wherein the processor is configured to: input the image to the pre-trained extractor of the edge device, extract the single feature of the image from a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device, and transmit the extracted single feature to the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0018" num="0017">The cloud sever may include a memory configured to store information on an extractor of the cloud sever including same structure as the extractor of the edge device and a reconstructor of the cloud sever, and a processor. The processor of the cloud sever may be configured to: receive the single feature from the edge device, input the single feature received from the extractor of the edge device to a portion of the extractor of the cloud sever, obtain an output feature ouput from the extractor of the cloud sever, input the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever, and obtain a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image ouput from the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0019" num="0018">The processor of the edge device may be configured to analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever, and determine a location of the split point with respect to the first layer based on an analysis result.</p>
<p id="p-0020" num="0019">The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0021" num="0020">The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0022" num="0021">The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0023" num="0022">In accordance with another aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a deep neural network-based object detection method, the method may comprise: inputting, by a processor included in an edge device, an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor of the edge device; extracting, by the processor included in the edge device, a single feature corresponding to the image from a first layer of the extractor corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device; transmitting, by the processor included in the edge device, the extracted single feature to a cloud sever; receiving, by a processor included in the cloud sever, the single feature from the edge device, wherein the cloud sever includes an extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a reconstructor; obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever; and obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0024" num="0023">The method may comprise: analyzing, by the processor included in the edge device, at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever; and determining a location of the split point with respect to the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device based on an analysis result.</p>
<p id="p-0025" num="0024">The extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</p>
<p id="p-0026" num="0025">The reconstructor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0027" num="0026">Each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0028" num="0027">A number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0029" num="0028">A number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</p>
<p id="p-0030" num="0029">According to the deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an object in an image can be rapidly detected in real time.</p>
<p id="p-0031" num="0030">The effects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned effect, and other effects not mentioned will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the description below.</p>
<?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?>
<description-of-drawings>
<heading id="h-0004" level="1">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading>
<p id="p-0032" num="0031"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a deep neural network-based object detection system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0033" num="0032"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a conceptual diagram of an edge device and a cloud sever according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0034" num="0033"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A to <b>3</b>C</figref> are diagrams for describing differences between prior arts and an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0035" num="0034"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a conceptual diagram for describing a deep neural network-based object detection system according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0036" num="0035"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a flowchart illustrating a deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
</description-of-drawings>
<?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?>
<heading id="h-0005" level="1">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading>
<p id="p-0037" num="0036">The advantages and features of the embodiments and the methods of accomplishing the embodiments will be clearly understood from the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. However, embodiments are not limited to those embodiments described, as embodiments may be implemented in various forms. It should be noted that the present embodiments are provided to make a full disclosure and also to allow those skilled in the art to know the full range of the embodiments. Therefore, the embodiments are to be defined only by the scope of the appended claims.</p>
<p id="p-0038" num="0037">Terms used in the present specification will be briefly described, and the present disclosure will be described in detail.</p>
<p id="p-0039" num="0038">In terms used in the present disclosure, general terms currently as widely used as possible while considering functions in the present disclosure are used. However, the terms may vary according to the intention or precedent of a technician working in the field, the emergence of new technologies, and the like. In addition, in certain cases, there are terms arbitrarily selected by the applicant, and in this case, the meaning of the terms will be described in detail in the description of the corresponding invention. Therefore, the terms used in the present disclosure should be defined based on the meaning of the terms and the overall contents of the present disclosure, not just the name of the terms.</p>
<p id="p-0040" num="0039">When it is described that a part in the overall specification “includes” a certain component, this means that other components may be further included instead of excluding other components unless specifically stated to the contrary.</p>
<p id="p-0041" num="0040">In addition, a term such as a “unit” or a “portion” used in the specification means a software component or a hardware component such as FPGA or ASIC, and the “unit” or the “portion” performs a certain role. However, the “unit” or the “portion” is not limited to software or hardware. The “portion” or the “unit” may be configured to be in an addressable storage medium, or may be configured to reproduce one or more processors. Thus, as an example, the “unit” or the “portion” includes components (such as software components, object-oriented software components, class components, and task components), processes, functions, properties, procedures, subroutines, segments of program code, drivers, firmware, microcode, circuits, data, database, data structures, tables, arrays, and variables. The functions provided in the components and “unit” may be combined into a smaller number of components and “units” or may be further divided into additional components and “units”.</p>
<p id="p-0042" num="0041">Hereinafter, the embodiment of the present disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings so that those of ordinary skill in the art may easily implement the present disclosure. In the drawings, portions not related to the description are omitted in order to clearly describe the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0043" num="0042"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a deep neural network-based object detection system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, and <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is a conceptual diagram for describing operations of an edge device and a cloud sever according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0044" num="0043">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>, a deep neural network-based object detection system <b>1</b> according to an embodiment of the present disclosure includes at least one edge device <b>100</b> that executes edge computing and a cloud sever <b>200</b> that receives data from the edge device <b>100</b>, executes cloud computing, and transmits the execution result to the edge.</p>
<p id="p-0045" num="0044">For example, the edge device <b>100</b> may correspond to a smart device, a drone, or a wearable device, but is not limited thereto.</p>
<p id="p-0046" num="0045">The edge device <b>100</b> may include a camera that acquires images, a memory that stores information on a pre-trained extractor, and a processor that controls components of the edge device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0047" num="0046">Basically, the edge device <b>100</b> can collect data, refine data, perform preprocessing such as sampling, cleaning, and combining data, and transmit preprocessing results to the cloud sever <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0048" num="0047">The functions of the edge device <b>100</b> can be designed in various manners. For example, the functions may be designed such that the edge device <b>100</b> processes data without sending the data to the cloud sever <b>200</b>, but in the present disclosure, description will focus on an embodiment in which the edge device <b>100</b> and the cloud sever <b>200</b> perform data processing in a split manner.</p>
<p id="p-0049" num="0048">In an embodiment, the edge device <b>100</b> may input an image acquired through a camera to a pre-trained extractor <b>110</b> and extract a single feature through a plurality of layers included in the extractor <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0050" num="0049">Here, the extractor may be an artificial neural network that is trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images and is trained to output a single feature when an image is input at the time of inference. Here, the extractor may correspond to an encoder of an auto encoder.</p>
<p id="p-0051" num="0050">In particular, the edge device <b>100</b> inputs the acquired image to the pre-trained extractor <b>110</b>, and may extract a single feature related to the image as an output of a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor <b>110</b> and transmit the single feature to the cloud sever <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0052" num="0051">Here, in order to determine the location of a predetermined split point for the plurality of layers, the edge device <b>100</b> may analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device <b>100</b> and the cloud sever <b>200</b>, a computing resource of the edge device <b>100</b>, and a computing resource of the cloud sever <b>200</b> and determine the location of the split point according to the analysis result. A layer corresponding to the split point may be referred to as a first layer.</p>
<p id="p-0053" num="0052">The cloud sever <b>200</b> may perform core processing, such as comprehensively performing tasks received from the edge device <b>100</b> or distributing some tasks to a specific edge device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0054" num="0053">Results processed in the cloud sever <b>200</b> may be delivered to the edge device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0055" num="0054">In an embodiment, the cloud sever <b>200</b> may detect an object of an image based on a single feature received from the edge device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0056" num="0055">To this end, the cloud sever <b>200</b> may include a pre-trained extractor <b>210</b>, a memory that stores information of a pre-trained reconstructor <b>220</b>, and a processor that controls components of the cloud sever <b>200</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0057" num="0056">The cloud sever <b>200</b> may obtain an output feature of the extractor <b>210</b> by inputting a single feature received from the edge device <b>100</b> to a second layer immediately after a first layer among a plurality of layers of the extractor <b>210</b>. Subsequently, the processor <b>200</b> may obtain a plurality of predetermined intermediate features required for object detection from the reconstructor <b>220</b> by inputting the output feature of the extractor <b>210</b> to the reconstructor <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0058" num="0057">Here, the extractor <b>210</b> may be an artificial neural network pre-trained to output an output feature when receiving training images and object information detected from the training images.</p>
<p id="p-0059" num="0058">The extractor <b>210</b> included in the cloud sever <b>200</b> is the same as the extractor <b>110</b> included in the edge device <b>100</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0060" num="0059">The reconstructor <b>220</b> may be an artificial neural network pre-trained to output a reconstructed feature when receiving training images and object information detected from the training images. The reconstructor <b>220</b> may correspond to a decoder of an auto encoder.</p>
<p id="p-0061" num="0060">Each layer constituting the reconstructor <b>220</b> is designed to have an inverse operation relationship with the layers of the extractor <b>210</b> to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0062" num="0061">In an embodiment, when the last layer of the extractor <b>110</b> is determined as a split point, the highest level feature is transmitted to the cloud sever <b>200</b> and passed through the reconstructor <b>220</b>. On the other hand, when splitting occurs in a previous layer of the extractor <b>110</b>, the edge device <b>100</b> transmits a low-level feature that has progressed to the corresponding layer to the cloud sever <b>200</b>. The cloud sever <b>200</b> inputs the received feature to the layer immediately after the split point of the extractor <b>210</b> to obtain a high-level output feature and passes the obtained output feature through the reconstructor <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0063" num="0062">The cloud sever <b>200</b> uses multi-level intermediate features obtained by inputting the output features to the reconstructor <b>220</b> for object detection later. Therefore, according to the present disclosure, even if the edge device <b>100</b> transmits a single feature to the cloud sever <b>200</b>, intermediate features can be obtained and thus normal object detection can be performed.</p>
<p id="p-0064" num="0063">Meanwhile, layers may output features of different sizes, and thus the cloud sever <b>200</b> may determine the second layer to which a received single feature will be input from among the plurality of layers included in the extractor <b>210</b> using the received single feature.</p>
<p id="p-0065" num="0064"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>3</b>A to <b>3</b>C</figref> are diagrams for describing differences between prior arts and an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0066" num="0065">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>A</figref>, a prior art is a case in which an edge device does not include an extractor and a cloud sever includes an extractor. In this case, the edge device transmits acquired image to the cloud sever, and the cloud sever inputs the image to the extractor and obtains a plurality of predetermined intermediate features to be used for object detection from the extractor. That is, the edge device only serves to acquire an image, and the cloud sever detects an object in the image based on an artificial intelligence model. In this case, when the edge device transmits an image to the cloud sever, there may be a problem in that it takes a long to transmit the image.</p>
<p id="p-0067" num="0066"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>B</figref> describes a case in which only an edge device includes an extractor. When a plurality of predetermined intermediate features is extracted from the extractor of the edge device and the extracted intermediate features are transmitted to a cloud sever, the cloud sever detects an object in an image based on the plurality of intermediate features. In this case, the performance of the edge device is limited and the problem related to image transmission time cannot be solved.</p>
<p id="p-0068" num="0067"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>3</b>C</figref> describes a case in which an edge device and a cloud sever include the same extractor. When a single feature is extracted from an intermediate layer among a plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device and transmitted to the cloud sever, the extractor of the cloud sever obtains a plurality of predetermined intermediate features by inputting the single feature to the layer immediately after the intermediate layer, and detects an object in an image based on the plurality of intermediate features. In this case, a delay time gain is limited because split layers are defined before the frontmost feature among a plurality of features is obtained.</p>
<p id="p-0069" num="0068">Distinguished from these prior arts, in the deep neural network-based object detection system <b>1</b> according to an embodiment of the present disclosure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>, the edge device <b>100</b> includes the extractor <b>110</b>, and the cloud sever <b>200</b> includes the extractor <b>210</b> and the reconstructor <b>220</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0070" num="0069">In summary, the edge device <b>100</b> analyzes a network speed between the edge device <b>100</b> and the processor <b>200</b> and at least one of the performances of the edge device <b>100</b> and the processor <b>200</b>, determines the location of a split point according to the analysis result, and transmits a single feature output from the first layer <b>11</b> corresponding to the split point to the cloud sever <b>200</b>. The cloud sever <b>200</b> may obtain a high-level feature by inputting the single feature to a layer <b>22</b> of the extractor <b>210</b> immediately after the first layer <b>11</b> from which the single feature transmitted from the edge device <b>100</b> is output. Subsequently, the cloud sever <b>200</b> may input the obtained feature to the reconstructor <b>220</b> to obtain a plurality of predetermined intermediate features required for object detection from the reconstructor <b>220</b>. Here, each layer constituting the reconstructor <b>220</b> has an inverse operation relationship with the layers of the extractor <b>210</b> to reconstruct intermediate features corresponding to a predetermined intermediate layer of the extractor <b>210</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0071" num="0070"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref> is a conceptual diagram for describing a deep neural network-based object detection system according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0072" num="0071">The deep neural network-based object detection system <b>1</b> described with reference to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIGS. <b>1</b> and <b>2</b></figref> can reduce the amount of transmission the edge device <b>100</b> through the reconstructor <b>220</b> of the cloud sever <b>200</b>, but a problem with respect to transmission time in a wireless network situation cannot be solved. Further, in the edge device <b>100</b> having limited resources, a significant delay time may be taken to execute the extractor <b>110</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0073" num="0072">In order to solve these problems, in the deep neural network-based object detection system <b>11</b> according to another embodiment of the present disclosure shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, the number of channels included in each layer of extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> may be less than the number of channels included in each layer of the extractor <b>210</b> shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>2</b></figref>.</p>
<p id="p-0074" num="0073">However, if only the number of channels of the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> is reduced, object detection accuracy is reduced. To compensate for this, asymmetric scaling in which the scale of the reconstructor <b>221</b> is increased is applied.</p>
<p id="p-0075" num="0074">An embodiment may be an asymmetric structure in which the number of channels of at least one of a plurality of layers included in the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> is less than the number of channels of at least one layer corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in a reconstructor <b>221</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0076" num="0075">Further, an embodiment may be an asymmetric structure in which the number of layers included in the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> may be different from the number of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b>. In this case, the number of layers included in the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> may be less than the number of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0077" num="0076">This is because the extractor <b>111</b> is executed in the edge device <b>100</b> with lower performance, whereas the reconstructor <b>221</b> is executed in the cloud sever <b>200</b> with better performance That is, since the extractor <b>111</b> is executed in the edge device <b>100</b>, the execution time is long (that is, delay time is long). Accordingly, the number of layers included in the extractor <b>111</b> is less than the number of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b>, and thus the delay time can be reduced. In addition, the number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor <b>111</b> is less than the number of channels of at least one layer corresponding to at least one of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b>, and thus the delay time can be reduced and the amount of data transmitted from the edge device <b>100</b> to the cloud sever <b>200</b> can be decreased.</p>
<p id="p-0078" num="0077">Meanwhile, if the number of layers included in the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> and/or the number of channels included in at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractors <b>111</b> and <b>211</b> are reduced, the performance may deteriorate (i.e. object detection accuracy decreases).</p>
<p id="p-0079" num="0078">Accordingly, as shown in <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>4</b></figref>, performance deterioration can be prevented by increasing the number of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b> and/or the number of channels included in at least one of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor <b>221</b>.</p>
<p id="p-0080" num="0079"><figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref> is a flowchart illustrating a deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p>
<p id="p-0081" num="0080">The deep neural network-based object detection method according to the present embodiment may be performed in substantially the same configuration as the system <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>. Accordingly, components identical to those of the system <b>1</b> of <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> are denoted by the same reference numerals, and redundant descriptions are omitted.</p>
<p id="p-0082" num="0081">Referring to <figref idref="DRAWINGS">FIG. <b>5</b></figref>, in the deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an edge device inputs an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor (S<b>110</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0083" num="0082">Next, the edge device extracts a single feature of the image as an output of a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor (S<b>120</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0084" num="0083">Next, the edge device transmits the extracted single feature to the cloud sever (S<b>130</b>). Next, the cloud sever including the same extractor as that of the edge device and a reconstructor obtains an output feature of the extractor by inputting the single feature to a second layer immediately after the first layer (S<b>140</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0085" num="0084">Next, the cloud sever obtains a plurality of intermediate features to be used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output features to the reconstructor (S<b>150</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0086" num="0085">Next, the cloud sever may detect the object in the image based on the plurality of intermediate features (S<b>160</b>).</p>
<p id="p-0087" num="0086">The deep neural network-based object detection system described above may be implemented by a computing device including at least some of a processor, a memory, a user input device, and a presentation device. The memory is a medium that stores computer-readable software coded such that a specific task can be performed when executed by the processor, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data. The processor may read and execute the computer-readable software, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data stored in the memory.</p>
<p id="p-0088" num="0087">The computing device may include a variety of devices such as smartphones, tablets, laptops, desktops, servers, and clients. The computing device may be a single stand-alone device or may include multiple computing devices operating in a distributed environment and cooperating with each other over a communications network.</p>
<p id="p-0089" num="0088">In addition, the above-described deep neural network-based object detection method may be executed by a computing device including a processor and a memory that stores computer-readable software coded to perform an object detection method using an artificial intelligence model when executed by the processor, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data structures.</p>
<p id="p-0090" num="0089">The present embodiments described above may be implemented through various means. For example, the present embodiments may be implemented by hardware, firmware, software, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0091" num="0090">In the case of implementation by hardware, an image diagnosis method using an artificial intelligence model according to the present embodiments may be implemented by one or more application specific integrated circuits (ASICs), digital signal processors (DSPs), digital signal processing devices (DSPDs), programmable logic devices (PLDs), field programmable gate arrays (FPGAs), processors, controllers, microcontrollers, or microprocessors.</p>
<p id="p-0092" num="0091">For example, an object detection method according to embodiments may be implemented using an artificial intelligence semiconductor device in which neurons and synapses of a deep neural network are implemented as semiconductor devices. In this case, the semiconductor devices may be currently used semiconductor devices such as SRAMs, DRAMs, and NANDs, next-generation semiconductor devices, RRAMs, STT MRAMs, PRAMs, or a combination thereof.</p>
<p id="p-0093" num="0092">When the object detection method according to the embodiments is implemented using an artificial intelligence semiconductor device, results (weights) of learning an auto-encoder as software may be transferred to synaptic mimic devices arranged in an array, or learning may be performed in the artificial intelligence semiconductor device.</p>
<p id="p-0094" num="0093">Combinations of steps in each flowchart attached to the present disclosure may be executed by computer program instructions. Since the computer program instructions can be mounted on a processor of a general-purpose computer, a special purpose computer, or other programmable data processing equipment, the instructions executed by the processor of the computer or other programmable data processing equipment create a means for performing the functions described in each step of the flowchart. The computer program instructions can also be stored on a computer-usable or computer-readable storage medium which can be directed to a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to implement a function in a specific manner. Accordingly, the instructions stored on the computer-usable or computer-readable recording medium can also produce an article of manufacture containing an instruction means which performs the functions described in each step of the flowchart. The computer program instructions can also be mounted on a computer or other programmable data processing equipment. Accordingly, a series of operational steps are performed on a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to create a computer-executable process, and it is also possible for instructions to perform a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to provide steps for performing the functions described in each step of the flowchart.</p>
<p id="p-0095" num="0094">In addition, each step may represent a module, a segment, or a portion of codes which contains one or more executable instructions for executing the specified logical function(s). It should also be noted that in some alternative embodiments, the functions mentioned in the steps may occur out of order. For example, two steps illustrated in succession may in fact be performed substantially simultaneously, or the steps may sometimes be performed in a reverse order depending on the corresponding function.</p>
<p id="p-0096" num="0095">The above description is merely exemplary description of the technical scope of the present disclosure, and it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications can be made without departing from original characteristics of the present disclosure. Therefore, the embodiments disclosed in the present disclosure are intended to explain, not to limit, the technical scope of the present disclosure, and the technical scope of the present disclosure is not limited by the embodiments. The protection scope of the present disclosure should be interpreted based on the following claims and it should be appreciated that all technical scopes included within a range equivalent thereto are included in the protection scope of the present disclosure.</p>
<?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?>
</description>
<us-claim-statement>What is claimed is:</us-claim-statement>
<claims id="claims">
<claim id="CLM-00001" num="00001">
<claim-text><b>1</b>. A cloud sever for detecting an object of an image based on a single feature received from an edge device, comprising:
<claim-text>a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a pre-trained reconstructor of the cloud sever; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the processor is configured to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a single feature of an image from the edge device, wherein the edge device includes an extractor having a plurality of layers and the single feature of the image is extracted by a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature received from the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature obtained from the extractor of the cloud sever to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00002" num="00002">
<claim-text><b>2</b>. The cloud sever of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
<claim-text>wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00003" num="00003">
<claim-text><b>3</b>. The cloud sever of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00002">claim 2</claim-ref>, wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
<claim-text>wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00004" num="00004">
<claim-text><b>4</b>. The cloud sever of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00005" num="00005">
<claim-text><b>5</b>. The cloud sever of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00006" num="00006">
<claim-text><b>6</b>. The cloud sever of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00001">claim 1</claim-ref>, wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00007" num="00007">
<claim-text><b>7</b>. An edge device for transmitting a single feature obtained from an image to a cloud sever, comprising:
<claim-text>a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the edge device having a plurality of layers; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processor,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the processor is configured to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>input the image to the pre-trained extractor of the edge device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>extract the single feature of the image from a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit the extracted single feature to the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00008" num="00008">
<claim-text><b>8</b>. The edge device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the cloud sever includes a memory configured to store information on an extractor of the cloud sever including same structure as the extractor of the edge device and a reconstructor of the cloud sever, and a processor,
<claim-text>wherein the processor of the cloud sever is configured to:</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive the single feature from the edge device,</claim-text>
<claim-text>input the single feature received from the extractor of the edge device to a portion of the extractor of the cloud sever,</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain an output feature ouput from the extractor of the cloud sever,</claim-text>
<claim-text>input the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtain a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image ouput from the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00009" num="00009">
<claim-text><b>9</b>. The edge device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00007">claim 7</claim-ref>, wherein the processor of the edge device is configured to analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever, and determine a location of the split point with respect to the first layer based on an analysis result.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00010" num="00010">
<claim-text><b>10</b>. The edge device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
<claim-text>wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00011" num="00011">
<claim-text><b>11</b>. The edge device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
<claim-text>wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00012" num="00012">
<claim-text><b>12</b>. The edge device of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00008">claim 8</claim-ref>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
<claim-text>wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00013" num="00013">
<claim-text><b>13</b>. A deep neural network-based object detection method comprising:
<claim-text>inputting, by a processor included in an edge device, an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor of the edge device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>extracting, by the processor included in the edge device, a single feature corresponding to the image from a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, by the processor included in the edge device, the extracted single feature to a cloud sever;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving, by a processor included in the cloud sever, the single feature from the edge device, wherein the cloud sever includes an extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a reconstructor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00014" num="00014">
<claim-text><b>14</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, further comprising:
<claim-text>analyzing, by the processor included in the edge device, at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining a location of the split point with respect to the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device based on an analysis result.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00015" num="00015">
<claim-text><b>15</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
<claim-text>wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00016" num="00016">
<claim-text><b>16</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
<claim-text>wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00017" num="00017">
<claim-text><b>17</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00018" num="00018">
<claim-text><b>18</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
<claim id="CLM-00019" num="00019">
<claim-text><b>19</b>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of <claim-ref idref="CLM-00013">claim 13</claim-ref>, wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</claim-text>
</claim>
</claims>
</us-patent-application></div><div class="header"><span>This XML file does not appear to have any style information associated with it. The document tree is shown below.</span><br /></div><div class="pretty-print"><div class="folder" id="folder0"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-patent-application<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">lang</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EN</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">dtd-version</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">v4.6 2022-02-17</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116.XML</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">status</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">PRODUCTION</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-patent-application</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">country</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">date-produced</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">20231101</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">date-publ</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">20231116</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder1"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-bibliographic-data-application<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">lang</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EN</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">country</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder2"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;publication-reference&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder3"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;document-id&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;doc-number&gt;</span><span>20230368518</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/doc-number&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;kind&gt;</span><span>A1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/kind&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/document-id&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/publication-reference&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder4"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;application-reference<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">appl-type</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">utility</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder5"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;document-id&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;doc-number&gt;</span><span>18197891</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/doc-number&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20230516</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/document-id&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/application-reference&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-application-series-code&gt;</span><span>18</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-application-series-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder6"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;priority-claims&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder7"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;priority-claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">01</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">kind</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">national</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;doc-number&gt;</span><span>10-2022-0059423</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/doc-number&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20220516</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/priority-claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/priority-claims&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder8"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classifications-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder9"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder10"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20060101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-level&gt;</span><span>A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-level&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>94</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>F</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder11"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder12"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder13"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder14"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20060101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-level&gt;</span><span>A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-level&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>77</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder15"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder16"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder17"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder18"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20060101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-level&gt;</span><span>A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-level&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>82</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder19"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder20"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder21"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder22"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20060101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/ipc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-level&gt;</span><span>A</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-level&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>774</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder23"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder24"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classifications-ipcr&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder25"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classifications-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder26"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder27"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder28"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20220101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>94</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>F</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder29"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder30"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;scheme-origination-code&gt;</span><span>C</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/scheme-origination-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder31"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;further-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder32"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder33"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20220101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>7715</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder34"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder35"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;scheme-origination-code&gt;</span><span>C</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/scheme-origination-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder36"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder37"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20220101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>82</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder38"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder39"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;scheme-origination-code&gt;</span><span>C</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/scheme-origination-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder40"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-cpc&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder41"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20220101</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/cpc-version-indicator&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;section&gt;</span><span>G</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/section&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;class&gt;</span><span>06</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/class&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subclass&gt;</span><span>V</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subclass&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;main-group&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/main-group&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;subgroup&gt;</span><span>774</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/subgroup&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;symbol-position&gt;</span><span>L</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/symbol-position&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-value&gt;</span><span>I</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-value&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder42"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;action-date&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;date&gt;</span><span>20231116</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/date&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/action-date&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder43"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;generating-office&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>US</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/generating-office&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-status&gt;</span><span>B</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-status&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;classification-data-source&gt;</span><span>H</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-data-source&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;scheme-origination-code&gt;</span><span>C</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/scheme-origination-code&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classification-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/further-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/classifications-cpc&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;invention-title<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">d2e61</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>DEEP NEURAL NETWORK-BASED OBJECT DETECTION METHOD, AND CLOUD SEVER AND EDGE DEVICE PERFORMING DEEP NEURAL NETWORK-BASED OBJECT DETECTION METHOD</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/invention-title&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder44"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-parties&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder45"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-applicants&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder46"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-applicant<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">app-type</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">applicant</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">applicant-authority-category</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">assignee</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder47"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;orgname&gt;</span><span>Research &amp; Business Foundation SUNGKYUNKWAN UNIVERSITY</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/orgname&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder48"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Suwon-si</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder49"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;residence&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/residence&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-applicant&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-applicants&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder50"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventors&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder51"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventor<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder52"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>LEE</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Joo Chan</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder53"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Suwon-si</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventor&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder54"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;inventor<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">sequence</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">01</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">designation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">us-only</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder55"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;last-name&gt;</span><span>KO</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/last-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;first-name&gt;</span><span>Jong Hwan</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/first-name&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder56"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Suwon-si</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventor&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/inventors&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-parties&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder57"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;assignees&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder58"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;assignee&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder59"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;addressbook&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;orgname&gt;</span><span>Research &amp; Business Foundation SUNGKYUNKWAN UNIVERSITY</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/orgname&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;role&gt;</span><span>03</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/role&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder60"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;address&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;city&gt;</span><span>Suwon-si</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/city&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;country&gt;</span><span>KR</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/country&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/address&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/addressbook&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/assignee&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/assignees&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-bibliographic-data-application&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder61"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;abstract<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">abstract</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0000</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The present disclosure relates to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method, and more particularly, to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object in an image in real time.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/abstract&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder62"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;drawings<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder63"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00000</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00000</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00000</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">138.35mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">108.54mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00000.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder64"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">129.20mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">151.72mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00001.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder65"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">178.39mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">122.34mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">orientation</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">landscape</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00002.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder66"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00003</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">138.35mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">135.81mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00003.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder67"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00004</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">160.27mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">151.38mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00004.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder68"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00005</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">175.18mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">130.39mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00005.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder69"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00006</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">126.32mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">158.83mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00006.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder70"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figure<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">Fig-EMI-D00007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;img<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">EMI-D00007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">he</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">179.92mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">wi</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">110.57mm</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">file</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">US20230368518A1-20231116-D00007.TIF</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">alt</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">embedded image</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-content</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">drawing</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">img-format</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">tif</span>"</span>/&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figure&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/drawings&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder71"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;description<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">description</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>TECHNICAL FIELD</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The present disclosure relates to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method, and more particularly, to a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object in an image in real time. This work was supported by Institute of Information &amp; communications Technology Planning &amp; Evaluation (IITP) grant funded by Korea government (MSIT) ([Project unique No.: 1711126132; Project No.: 2019-0-00421-003; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Artificial Intelligence Graduate School Program], [Project unique No.: 1711139517; Project No.: 2021-0-02068-001; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Development for Artificial Intelligence Innovative Hub], and [Project unique No.: 1711139247; Project No.: 2021-0-02052-001; R&amp;D project: Information Communication Broadcasting Innovative Talent Development Project; and Research Project Title: Development for Artificial Intelligence System on a Chip for Smart Mobility]).</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>BACKGROUND</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0002</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>With the recent development of deep neural networks (DNNs), excellent performance has been implemented in various tasks related to computer vision. However, due to resource constraints, it is still difficult for edge devices to acquire images in real time and perform real-time inference of DNN models with complex deep neural networks. In this case, images obtained by an edge device can be transmitted to a cloud sever equipped with a high-performance GPU for processing. However, due to the characteristics of an edge device that needs to use a wireless network, it may take a long time to transmit images. In order to solve this problem, it is possible to use an edge-cloud split inference technique in which an edge device uses a part of a deep neural network, and features smaller than the original image are transmitted to a cloud sever for processing.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0003</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In general, since the size of a feature decreases as the number of layers for extracting a feature increases, an appropriate split point needs to be present for each network.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0004</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>However, unlike image classifiers, general deep neural network-based object detectors need to use multiple layers of features in order to effectively detect objects of various sizes.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0005</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>That is, object detection is not performed using only the last feature of a feature-extracting layer, but predetermined intermediate features among a plurality of feature-extracting layers are also required.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0006</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>For this reason, the amount of transmission increases in a split inference situation, and thus it is difficult to find an appropriate split point in a general object detector layer.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>SUMMARY</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0008</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In view of the above, the present disclosure provides a deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method capable of rapidly detecting an object of an image in real time.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0009</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0008</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Objects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned object, and other objects not mentioned will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the description below.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0010</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0009</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The aspects of the present disclosure are not limited to the foregoing, and other aspects not mentioned herein will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the following description.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0011</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0010</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In accordance with an aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a cloud sever for detecting an object of an image based on a single feature received from an edge device, the cloud sever may comprise: a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a pre-trained reconstructor of the cloud sever; and a processor, wherein the processor is configured to: receive a single feature of an image from the edge device, wherein the edge device includes an extractor having a plurality of layers and the single feature of the image is extracted by a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device; and obtain an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature received from the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever, and detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature obtained from the extractor of the cloud sever to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0012</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0011</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0013</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0012</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The reconstructor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0014</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0015</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0014</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>A number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0016</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0015</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>A number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0017</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0016</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In accordance with another aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided an edge device for transmitting a single feature obtained from an image to a cloud sever, the cloud sever may comprise: a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the edge device having a plurality of layers; and a processor, wherein the processor is configured to: input the image to the pre-trained extractor of the edge device, extract the single feature of the image from a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device, and transmit the extracted single feature to the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0018</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0017</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The cloud sever may include a memory configured to store information on an extractor of the cloud sever including same structure as the extractor of the edge device and a reconstructor of the cloud sever, and a processor. The processor of the cloud sever may be configured to: receive the single feature from the edge device, input the single feature received from the extractor of the edge device to a portion of the extractor of the cloud sever, obtain an output feature ouput from the extractor of the cloud sever, input the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever, and obtain a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image ouput from the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0019</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0018</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The processor of the edge device may be configured to analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever, and determine a location of the split point with respect to the first layer based on an analysis result.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0020</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0019</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0021</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0020</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0022</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0021</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may include a plurality of layers, and a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0023</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0022</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In accordance with another aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a deep neural network-based object detection method, the method may comprise: inputting, by a processor included in an edge device, an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor of the edge device; extracting, by the processor included in the edge device, a single feature corresponding to the image from a first layer of the extractor corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device; transmitting, by the processor included in the edge device, the extracted single feature to a cloud sever; receiving, by a processor included in the cloud sever, the single feature from the edge device, wherein the cloud sever includes an extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a reconstructor; obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever; and obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0024</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0023</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The method may comprise: analyzing, by the processor included in the edge device, at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever; and determining a location of the split point with respect to the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device based on an analysis result.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0025</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0024</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0026</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0025</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The reconstructor of the cloud sever may be an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and the reconstructor of the cloud sever may be trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0027</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0026</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever may have an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0028</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0027</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>A number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0029</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0028</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>A number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever may be less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0030</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0029</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>According to the deep neural network-based object detection device, system, and method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an object in an image can be rapidly detected in real time.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0031</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0030</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The effects of the present disclosure are not limited to the aforementioned effect, and other effects not mentioned will be clearly understood by those skilled in the art from the description below.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?summary-of-invention description="Summary of Invention" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder72"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;description-of-drawings&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder73"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0032</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0031</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder74"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a deep neural network-based object detection system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder75"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0033</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0032</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder76"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a conceptual diagram of an edge device and a cloud sever according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder77"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0034</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0033</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder78"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIGS. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> are diagrams for describing differences between prior arts and an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder79"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0035</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0034</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder80"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a conceptual diagram for describing a deep neural network-based object detection system according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder81"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0036</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0035</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder82"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a flowchart illustrating a deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/description-of-drawings&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?brief-description-of-drawings description="Brief Description of Drawings" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="lead"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;heading<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">h-0005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">level</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">1</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/heading&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0037</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0036</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The advantages and features of the embodiments and the methods of accomplishing the embodiments will be clearly understood from the following description taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. However, embodiments are not limited to those embodiments described, as embodiments may be implemented in various forms. It should be noted that the present embodiments are provided to make a full disclosure and also to allow those skilled in the art to know the full range of the embodiments. Therefore, the embodiments are to be defined only by the scope of the appended claims.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0038</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0037</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Terms used in the present specification will be briefly described, and the present disclosure will be described in detail.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0039</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0038</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In terms used in the present disclosure, general terms currently as widely used as possible while considering functions in the present disclosure are used. However, the terms may vary according to the intention or precedent of a technician working in the field, the emergence of new technologies, and the like. In addition, in certain cases, there are terms arbitrarily selected by the applicant, and in this case, the meaning of the terms will be described in detail in the description of the corresponding invention. Therefore, the terms used in the present disclosure should be defined based on the meaning of the terms and the overall contents of the present disclosure, not just the name of the terms.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0040</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0039</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>When it is described that a part in the overall specification “includes” a certain component, this means that other components may be further included instead of excluding other components unless specifically stated to the contrary.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0041</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0040</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In addition, a term such as a “unit” or a “portion” used in the specification means a software component or a hardware component such as FPGA or ASIC, and the “unit” or the “portion” performs a certain role. However, the “unit” or the “portion” is not limited to software or hardware. The “portion” or the “unit” may be configured to be in an addressable storage medium, or may be configured to reproduce one or more processors. Thus, as an example, the “unit” or the “portion” includes components (such as software components, object-oriented software components, class components, and task components), processes, functions, properties, procedures, subroutines, segments of program code, drivers, firmware, microcode, circuits, data, database, data structures, tables, arrays, and variables. The functions provided in the components and “unit” may be combined into a smaller number of components and “units” or may be further divided into additional components and “units”.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0042</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0041</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Hereinafter, the embodiment of the present disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings so that those of ordinary skill in the art may easily implement the present disclosure. In the drawings, portions not related to the description are omitted in order to clearly describe the present disclosure.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder83"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0043</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0042</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder84"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a deep neural network-based object detection system according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, and </span><div class="folder" id="folder85"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a conceptual diagram for describing operations of an edge device and a cloud sever according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder86"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0044</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0043</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Referring to </span><div class="folder" id="folder87"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, a deep neural network-based object detection system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> according to an embodiment of the present disclosure includes at least one edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> that executes edge computing and a cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> that receives data from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, executes cloud computing, and transmits the execution result to the edge.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder88"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0045</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0044</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>For example, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may correspond to a smart device, a drone, or a wearable device, but is not limited thereto.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder89"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0046</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0045</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may include a camera that acquires images, a memory that stores information on a pre-trained extractor, and a processor that controls components of the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder90"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0047</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0046</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Basically, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can collect data, refine data, perform preprocessing such as sampling, cleaning, and combining data, and transmit preprocessing results to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder91"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0048</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0047</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The functions of the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can be designed in various manners. For example, the functions may be designed such that the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> processes data without sending the data to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, but in the present disclosure, description will focus on an embodiment in which the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> perform data processing in a split manner.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder92"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0049</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0048</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In an embodiment, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may input an image acquired through a camera to a pre-trained extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and extract a single feature through a plurality of layers included in the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0050</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0049</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Here, the extractor may be an artificial neural network that is trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images and is trained to output a single feature when an image is input at the time of inference. Here, the extractor may correspond to an encoder of an auto encoder.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder93"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0051</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0050</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In particular, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> inputs the acquired image to the pre-trained extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and may extract a single feature related to the image as an output of a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and transmit the single feature to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder94"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0052</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0051</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Here, in order to determine the location of a predetermined split point for the plurality of layers, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, a computing resource of the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and a computing resource of the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and determine the location of the split point according to the analysis result. A layer corresponding to the split point may be referred to as a first layer.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder95"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0053</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0052</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may perform core processing, such as comprehensively performing tasks received from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> or distributing some tasks to a specific edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder96"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0054</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0053</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Results processed in the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be delivered to the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder97"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0055</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0054</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In an embodiment, the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may detect an object of an image based on a single feature received from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder98"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0056</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0055</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>To this end, the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may include a pre-trained extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, a memory that stores information of a pre-trained reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and a processor that controls components of the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder99"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0057</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0056</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may obtain an output feature of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> by inputting a single feature received from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to a second layer immediately after a first layer among a plurality of layers of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. Subsequently, the processor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may obtain a plurality of predetermined intermediate features required for object detection from the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> by inputting the output feature of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder100"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0058</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0057</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Here, the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be an artificial neural network pre-trained to output an output feature when receiving training images and object information detected from the training images.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder101"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0059</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0058</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> included in the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is the same as the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> included in the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder102"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0060</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0059</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be an artificial neural network pre-trained to output a reconstructed feature when receiving training images and object information detected from the training images. The reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may correspond to a decoder of an auto encoder.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder103"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0061</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0060</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Each layer constituting the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is designed to have an inverse operation relationship with the layers of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder104"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0062</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0061</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In an embodiment, when the last layer of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is determined as a split point, the highest level feature is transmitted to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and passed through the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. On the other hand, when splitting occurs in a previous layer of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> transmits a low-level feature that has progressed to the corresponding layer to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> inputs the received feature to the layer immediately after the split point of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to obtain a high-level output feature and passes the obtained output feature through the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder105"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0063</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0062</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> uses multi-level intermediate features obtained by inputting the output features to the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> for object detection later. Therefore, according to the present disclosure, even if the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> transmits a single feature to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, intermediate features can be obtained and thus normal object detection can be performed.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder106"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0064</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0063</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Meanwhile, layers may output features of different sizes, and thus the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may determine the second layer to which a received single feature will be input from among the plurality of layers included in the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> using the received single feature.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder107"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0065</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0064</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder108"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIGS. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A to </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> are diagrams for describing differences between prior arts and an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder109"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0066</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0065</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Referring to </span><div class="folder" id="folder110"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>A</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, a prior art is a case in which an edge device does not include an extractor and a cloud sever includes an extractor. In this case, the edge device transmits acquired image to the cloud sever, and the cloud sever inputs the image to the extractor and obtains a plurality of predetermined intermediate features to be used for object detection from the extractor. That is, the edge device only serves to acquire an image, and the cloud sever detects an object in the image based on an artificial intelligence model. In this case, when the edge device transmits an image to the cloud sever, there may be a problem in that it takes a long to transmit the image.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder111"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0067</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0066</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder112"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>B</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> describes a case in which only an edge device includes an extractor. When a plurality of predetermined intermediate features is extracted from the extractor of the edge device and the extracted intermediate features are transmitted to a cloud sever, the cloud sever detects an object in an image based on the plurality of intermediate features. In this case, the performance of the edge device is limited and the problem related to image transmission time cannot be solved.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder113"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0068</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0067</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder114"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>C</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> describes a case in which an edge device and a cloud sever include the same extractor. When a single feature is extracted from an intermediate layer among a plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device and transmitted to the cloud sever, the extractor of the cloud sever obtains a plurality of predetermined intermediate features by inputting the single feature to the layer immediately after the intermediate layer, and detects an object in an image based on the plurality of intermediate features. In this case, a delay time gain is limited because split layers are defined before the frontmost feature among a plurality of features is obtained.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder115"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0069</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0068</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Distinguished from these prior arts, in the deep neural network-based object detection system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> according to an embodiment of the present disclosure shown in </span><div class="folder" id="folder116"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> includes the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> includes the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder117"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0070</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0069</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In summary, the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> analyzes a network speed between the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the processor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and at least one of the performances of the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and the processor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, determines the location of a split point according to the analysis result, and transmits a single feature output from the first layer </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> corresponding to the split point to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may obtain a high-level feature by inputting the single feature to a layer </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>22</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> immediately after the first layer </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> from which the single feature transmitted from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is output. Subsequently, the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may input the obtained feature to the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to obtain a plurality of predetermined intermediate features required for object detection from the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. Here, each layer constituting the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> has an inverse operation relationship with the layers of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to reconstruct intermediate features corresponding to a predetermined intermediate layer of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder118"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0071</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0070</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder119"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a conceptual diagram for describing a deep neural network-based object detection system according to another embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder120"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0072</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0071</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The deep neural network-based object detection system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> described with reference to </span><div class="folder" id="folder121"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIGS. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> can reduce the amount of transmission the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> through the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>220</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, but a problem with respect to transmission time in a wireless network situation cannot be solved. Further, in the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> having limited resources, a significant delay time may be taken to execute the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder122"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0073</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0072</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>In order to solve these problems, in the deep neural network-based object detection system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> according to another embodiment of the present disclosure shown in </span><div class="folder" id="folder123"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, the number of channels included in each layer of extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be less than the number of channels included in each layer of the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>210</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> shown in </span><div class="folder" id="folder124"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder125"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0074</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0073</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>However, if only the number of channels of the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is reduced, object detection accuracy is reduced. To compensate for this, asymmetric scaling in which the scale of the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is increased is applied.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder126"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0075</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0074</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>An embodiment may be an asymmetric structure in which the number of channels of at least one of a plurality of layers included in the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is less than the number of channels of at least one layer corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in a reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder127"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0076</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0075</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Further, an embodiment may be an asymmetric structure in which the number of layers included in the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be different from the number of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. In this case, the number of layers included in the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> may be less than the number of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder128"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0077</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0076</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>This is because the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is executed in the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> with lower performance, whereas the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is executed in the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> with better performance That is, since the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is executed in the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, the execution time is long (that is, delay time is long). Accordingly, the number of layers included in the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is less than the number of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and thus the delay time can be reduced. In addition, the number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> is less than the number of channels of at least one layer corresponding to at least one of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>, and thus the delay time can be reduced and the amount of data transmitted from the edge device </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>100</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> to the cloud sever </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>200</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> can be decreased.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder129"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0078</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0077</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Meanwhile, if the number of layers included in the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and/or the number of channels included in at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractors </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>111</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>211</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> are reduced, the performance may deteriorate (i.e. object detection accuracy decreases).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder130"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0079</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0078</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Accordingly, as shown in </span><div class="folder" id="folder131"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, performance deterioration can be prevented by increasing the number of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> and/or the number of channels included in at least one of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>221</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder132"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0080</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0079</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="folder" id="folder133"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> is a flowchart illustrating a deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder134"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0081</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0080</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>The deep neural network-based object detection method according to the present embodiment may be performed in substantially the same configuration as the system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of </span><div class="folder" id="folder135"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>. Accordingly, components identical to those of the system </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span> of </span><div class="folder" id="folder136"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span> are denoted by the same reference numerals, and redundant descriptions are omitted.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder137"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0082</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0081</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Referring to </span><div class="folder" id="folder138"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;figref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">DRAWINGS</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>FIG. </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/figref&gt;</span></div></div><span>, in the deep neural network-based object detection method according to an embodiment of the present disclosure, an edge device inputs an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>110</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder139"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0083</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0082</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Next, the edge device extracts a single feature of the image as an output of a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>120</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder140"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0084</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0083</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Next, the edge device transmits the extracted single feature to the cloud sever (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>130</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>). Next, the cloud sever including the same extractor as that of the edge device and a reconstructor obtains an output feature of the extractor by inputting the single feature to a second layer immediately after the first layer (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>140</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder141"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0085</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0084</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Next, the cloud sever obtains a plurality of intermediate features to be used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output features to the reconstructor (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>150</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder142"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0086</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0085</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>Next, the cloud sever may detect the object in the image based on the plurality of intermediate features (S</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>160</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>).</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0087</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0086</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The deep neural network-based object detection system described above may be implemented by a computing device including at least some of a processor, a memory, a user input device, and a presentation device. The memory is a medium that stores computer-readable software coded such that a specific task can be performed when executed by the processor, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data. The processor may read and execute the computer-readable software, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data stored in the memory.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0088</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0087</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The computing device may include a variety of devices such as smartphones, tablets, laptops, desktops, servers, and clients. The computing device may be a single stand-alone device or may include multiple computing devices operating in a distributed environment and cooperating with each other over a communications network.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0089</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0088</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In addition, the above-described deep neural network-based object detection method may be executed by a computing device including a processor and a memory that stores computer-readable software coded to perform an object detection method using an artificial intelligence model when executed by the processor, applications, program modules, routines, instructions, and/or data structures.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0090</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0089</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The present embodiments described above may be implemented through various means. For example, the present embodiments may be implemented by hardware, firmware, software, or a combination thereof.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0091</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0090</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In the case of implementation by hardware, an image diagnosis method using an artificial intelligence model according to the present embodiments may be implemented by one or more application specific integrated circuits (ASICs), digital signal processors (DSPs), digital signal processing devices (DSPDs), programmable logic devices (PLDs), field programmable gate arrays (FPGAs), processors, controllers, microcontrollers, or microprocessors.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0092</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0091</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>For example, an object detection method according to embodiments may be implemented using an artificial intelligence semiconductor device in which neurons and synapses of a deep neural network are implemented as semiconductor devices. In this case, the semiconductor devices may be currently used semiconductor devices such as SRAMs, DRAMs, and NANDs, next-generation semiconductor devices, RRAMs, STT MRAMs, PRAMs, or a combination thereof.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0093</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0092</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>When the object detection method according to the embodiments is implemented using an artificial intelligence semiconductor device, results (weights) of learning an auto-encoder as software may be transferred to synaptic mimic devices arranged in an array, or learning may be performed in the artificial intelligence semiconductor device.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0094</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0093</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>Combinations of steps in each flowchart attached to the present disclosure may be executed by computer program instructions. Since the computer program instructions can be mounted on a processor of a general-purpose computer, a special purpose computer, or other programmable data processing equipment, the instructions executed by the processor of the computer or other programmable data processing equipment create a means for performing the functions described in each step of the flowchart. The computer program instructions can also be stored on a computer-usable or computer-readable storage medium which can be directed to a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to implement a function in a specific manner. Accordingly, the instructions stored on the computer-usable or computer-readable recording medium can also produce an article of manufacture containing an instruction means which performs the functions described in each step of the flowchart. The computer program instructions can also be mounted on a computer or other programmable data processing equipment. Accordingly, a series of operational steps are performed on a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to create a computer-executable process, and it is also possible for instructions to perform a computer or other programmable data processing equipment to provide steps for performing the functions described in each step of the flowchart.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0095</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0094</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>In addition, each step may represent a module, a segment, or a portion of codes which contains one or more executable instructions for executing the specified logical function(s). It should also be noted that in some alternative embodiments, the functions mentioned in the steps may occur out of order. For example, two steps illustrated in succession may in fact be performed substantially simultaneously, or the steps may sometimes be performed in a reverse order depending on the corresponding function.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;p<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">p-0096</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">0095</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>The above description is merely exemplary description of the technical scope of the present disclosure, and it will be understood by those skilled in the art that various changes and modifications can be made without departing from original characteristics of the present disclosure. Therefore, the embodiments disclosed in the present disclosure are intended to explain, not to limit, the technical scope of the present disclosure, and the technical scope of the present disclosure is not limited by the embodiments. The protection scope of the present disclosure should be interpreted based on the following claims and it should be appreciated that all technical scopes included within a range equivalent thereto are included in the protection scope of the present disclosure.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/p&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="comment html-comment">&lt;?detailed-description description="Detailed Description" end="tail"?&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/description&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;us-claim-statement&gt;</span><span>What is claimed is:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-claim-statement&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder143"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claims<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">claims</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder144"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder145"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A cloud sever for detecting an object of an image based on a single feature received from an edge device, comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a pre-trained reconstructor of the cloud sever; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>a processor,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the processor is configured to:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>receive a single feature of an image from the edge device, wherein the edge device includes an extractor having a plurality of layers and the single feature of the image is extracted by a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers of the extractor of the edge device; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtain an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature received from the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever, and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature obtained from the extractor of the cloud sever to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder146"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00002</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder147"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder148"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00003</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00003</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder149"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>3</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00002</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 2</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder150"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00004</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00004</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder151"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>4</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder152"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00005</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00005</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder153"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>5</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder154"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00006</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00006</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder155"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>6</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The cloud sever of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00001</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 1</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder156"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder157"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. An edge device for transmitting a single feature obtained from an image to a cloud sever, comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>a memory configured to store information on a pre-trained extractor of the edge device having a plurality of layers; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>a processor,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the processor is configured to:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>input the image to the pre-trained extractor of the edge device,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>extract the single feature of the image from a first layer corresponding to a predetermined split point among the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device, and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>transmit the extracted single feature to the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder158"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00008</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00008</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder159"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>8</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The edge device of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the cloud sever includes a memory configured to store information on an extractor of the cloud sever including same structure as the extractor of the edge device and a reconstructor of the cloud sever, and a processor,
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the processor of the cloud sever is configured to:</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>receive the single feature from the edge device,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>input the single feature received from the extractor of the edge device to a portion of the extractor of the cloud sever,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtain an output feature ouput from the extractor of the cloud sever,</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>input the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever, and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtain a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image ouput from the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder160"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00009</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00009</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder161"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>9</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The edge device of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00007</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 7</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the processor of the edge device is configured to analyze at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever, and determine a location of the split point with respect to the first layer based on an analysis result.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder162"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00010</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00010</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder163"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>10</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The edge device of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00008</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 8</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder164"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00011</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00011</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder165"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>11</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The edge device of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00008</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 8</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder166"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00012</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00012</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder167"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>12</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The edge device of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00008</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 8</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the extractor of the cloud sever and the reconstructor of the cloud sever includes a plurality of layers, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder168"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder169"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. A deep neural network-based object detection method comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>inputting, by a processor included in an edge device, an acquired image to a pre-trained extractor of the edge device;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>extracting, by the processor included in the edge device, a single feature corresponding to the image from a first layer of the extractor of the edge device corresponding to a predetermined split point among a plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>transmitting, by the processor included in the edge device, the extracted single feature to a cloud sever;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>receiving, by a processor included in the cloud sever, the single feature from the edge device, wherein the cloud sever includes an extractor of the cloud sever having a first layer and a second layer and a reconstructor;</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, an output feature of the extractor of the cloud sever by inputting the single feature to the second layer included in the extractor of the cloud sever; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>obtaining, by the processor included in the cloud sever, a plurality of intermediate features used to detect an object in the image by inputting the output feature to the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder170"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00014</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00014</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder171"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>14</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, further comprising:
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>analyzing, by the processor included in the edge device, at least one of a network resource between the edge device and the cloud sever, a computing resource of the edge device, and a computing resource of the cloud sever; and</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>determining a location of the split point with respect to the first layer included in the extractor of the edge device based on an analysis result.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder172"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00015</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00015</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder173"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>15</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is trained to output a single feature corresponding to each of the training images.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder174"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00016</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00016</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder175"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>16</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is an artificial neural network trained by receiving training images and object information detected from the training images, and
</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span><span>wherein the reconstructor of the cloud sever is trained to output a plurality of features corresponding to the single feature output from the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder176"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00017</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00017</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder177"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>17</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein each layer of the reconstructor of the cloud sever has an inverse operation relationship with each layer of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever to reconstruct predetermined intermediate layer features of the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder178"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00018</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00018</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder179"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>18</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein a number of channels of at least one of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of channels corresponding to at least one of a plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder180"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">id</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00019</span>"</span><span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">num</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">00019</span>"</span>&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><span>
</span><div class="folder" id="folder181"><div class="line"><span class="folder-button fold"></span><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-text&gt;</span></div><div class="opened"><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;b&gt;</span><span>19</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/b&gt;</span></div><span>. The deep neural network-based object detection method of </span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;claim-ref<span class="html-attribute"> <span class="html-attribute-name">idref</span>="<span class="html-attribute-value">CLM-00013</span>"</span>&gt;</span><span>claim 13</span><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-ref&gt;</span></div><span>, wherein a number of the plurality of layers included in the extractor of the edge device or the extractor of the cloud sever is less than a number of the plurality of layers included in the reconstructor of the cloud sever.</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim-text&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claim&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/claims&gt;</span></div></div><span>
</span></div><span class="folded hidden">...</span><div class="line"><span class="html-tag">&lt;/us-patent-application&gt;</span></div></div></div></body></html>